<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quarantine Chronicles</title>
    <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Quarantine Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:45:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/johannabernatzky.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第九天：庆祝</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-1/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-1/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;席卷欧洲的丧尸病毒终于被清除完毕了，新闻宣布解除宵禁令，生活也重回正轨。凯丽没有经历过战争，没有感受过冷战的恐惧，却经历了如同战时的丧尸病毒封城居家禁令。不过，既然生活重归平静，那她也开始计划要如何与朋友们一同庆祝。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Europe has finally rid itself of the zombie virus, newspapers report the lifting of all restrictions, life returns to normal. Kelly, not having lived through any wars, having grown up without a trace of the Cold War’s existential dread, now knows what it is like to live under lockdown in a city besieged. But now that normality has reinstated itself, she begins to plan a celebration with her friends.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;眼下凯丽还有生长得很好的绿叶蔬菜，或许她可以办一个绿色蔬菜派对，邀请朋友们一起吃菜。但只有沙拉吃也未免有些无聊，她还需要想一些新点子，把这些蔬菜利用起来。这些蔬菜也是她这几个月独居生活的见证了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Some of her beautifully grown green vegetables remain, maybe she will invite her friends to a vegetable feast. Then again, a salad-only feast seems a little boring. She will have to think of some other dishes to show off her greens. After all, they have documented her solitary life over the past months so well.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;在凯丽搜索创意菜谱时，娜塔莉打电话邀请她参加葡萄丰收酿酒派对，品尝他们家今年收获的葡萄，还有先前闭门保命期间酿的的果酒。危险一过，大家都沉浸在对未来生活的期许中，都想好好庆祝被迫分隔开的特殊时期的终结。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As she looks for recipes, Kelly receives a call from Natalie, who invites her to a party of grape harvesting and wine making. There will be freshly picked grapes to taste, and the wine the family has been maturing during the lockdown. With the danger defeated, dreams for the future start to sprout again, people no longer forced into separation now long for celebration.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;独居躲避丧尸病毒时，凯丽头一回体验对未来的恐惧、不安与不知生活何时恢复正常的绝望，才发觉原本生活的世界是如此便利和连通。一个人独处的时候，她想了很多，现在凯丽只想和亲朋好友们好好庆祝充满希望的正常生活，开启新的篇章。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Locked away in fear of the zombie virus, Kelly feared for her future for the first time in her life. The anxiety, not knowing when life would fall back into place put it all into perspective. She now understands how comfortable, how connected her life used to be. She had a lot of time to think, left all by herself.  Now all she wants to do is celebrate the hopeful ordinariness of life, she wants to turn over the page.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Pexels from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-1/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 9: Full Moon at Orchard House</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Leon lived on the tenth floor of Orchard House. Whoever had chosen this name must have possessed an obscene dose of optimism, Orchard House was about as far from green as you could get. Layers of concrete squashed over each other, the building imposed its presence on the neighbourhood like a prison guard. Try as you might, wherever you went one of its windows was watching you.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;里昂住在果园楼的十楼。不知取名人何者，但一定是极其乐观的人。只要你看看果园楼，就知道这里和绿色毫不沾边。取而代之的是一层又一层的混凝土，显得这座楼像是邻近地区的看守狱卒一样。你大可一试，无论走到哪里，总会感觉到某个窗子里传来的注视。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Most days, Leon didn’t look forward much to going home. School was bright and exciting, full of new things to be learned, while home was tinged with grey and burdened with worries that seeped out of the walls on rainy days. But once every month, when the moon was at its brightest, Orchard House transformed. While to a passer-by it wouldn’t seem any different, anyone inside the building when the last slice of sun disappeared behind the horizon witnessed the change.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;绝大多数日子里，里昂并不期待回家。学校是那么明亮，活力四射，充满全新的知识。他的家则是灰暗的，每逢雨天，他总是要担心墙会渗出水来。每逢满月那天，月色皎洁明亮，果园楼总会发生奇幻的变化。过路人瞧去并无不同，但楼内居民却能在最后一丝夕照退却到地平线后，发现果园楼的变化。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It started with a tremor. Picture frames trembling on the walls, chairs jumping around. Then a crackling silence, and finally the sharp ring of a bell. Leon jumped up from his bed and ran into the living room, where he found his sister Clara already waiting, carrying a plate of biscuits. Their mum was standing by the door, beckoning excitedly. Through the crack at the bottom of the door, Leon saw a shimmering light.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;首先，果园楼会有一丝颤动。墙上的画框会摇晃，楼中的椅子会晃动。随之而来的是沉默，最终是钟声敲响。里昂跳下床，跑进客厅，见到妹妹克拉拉也在等待，带着一盘饼干。妈妈倚靠房门，心情激动。里昂看见从门边缝隙流入家中的闪亮月光。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Today he was the one to open the door. He knew that tonight, it would not lead to the naked corridor with its clinically white neon lights. Tonight the door opened on a celebration. A meadow stretched out in front of Leon and his family, soft green grass tickled their feet as they stepped onto it. And there, he could see doors all around the meadow opening. Some people came alone, some in twos and threes. All carried food and smiles to be shared. From somewhere Leon could hear music, maybe one of their neighbours had left their radio on.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今晚是由里昂开门。他知道今晚门后不再是空荡荡的映着白月光的长廊，取而代之的是一场庆典。开门之后，里昂和他的家人来到一片草坪上，他们光脚踏上草坪，柔软的小草挠的他们的脚板有点痒。这里还有独自前来的人，有三五成群的人。所有人分享着食物和笑容。里昂听见不知何处传来的音乐，可能是邻居忘记关收音机了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The full moon shone quietly over Orchard House, illuminating the festive meadow. It watched over the celebration of life, of another month of discoveries, losses, heartbreaks, successes, ready to be shared with a friendly ear eager to listen. Tonight, neighbours became friends under the soft glow, and even though they knew that the night could not last forever, in this moment they were happy.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;圆月的光芒静静地洒落在果园楼，照亮了喜庆的草坪，看着人们庆祝着生命、新的发现、损失、心碎、成功，做好了聆听故事的准备。今晚，住客们在柔光下作伴，他们虽知满月的光芒不会永远持续，但此时此刻他们是快乐的。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Free-Photos on Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第八天：海边散步</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a poem full of social distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我在海边散步，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I walk on the beach&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;享受着地中海的阳光沙滩，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bask in the Mediterranean sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;喝着鲜榨橙子，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fresh orange juice in hand&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;和人群保持着距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I keep my distance from the people&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我感到很安全。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;And feel safe.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一声问好，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A greeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;有人跟来搭讪。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A stranger strikes up a conversation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;恰好我一个人也无聊，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bored with myself&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;回了他几句。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I exchange a few words with him.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;但陌生人没有保持社交距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;But the stranger approaches past social distancing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;企图调情，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For a flirt.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让我烦躁和惊恐。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I am anxious and scared.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;疫情期间，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In this pandemic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;没有两米社交距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two-metre closeness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;没有口罩，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unmasked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让我惧怕。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scares me.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Sophie.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 8: Alone at Lidl</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a poem full of social distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I wonder why&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我想知道&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;We don’t look at each other anymore&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;大家为何不再看彼此一眼&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pushing our shopping carts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;推挤着购物车&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;past      each      other&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;经 过 彼此&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;We stare resolutely ahead&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我们盯着远处&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Or find a particularly eye-catching&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;或是发现了特别抢眼的&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bunch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;of&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;束&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bananas     to investigate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;香蕉用来观察&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maybe we are scared&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;也许我们都害怕&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;That this small human interaction might be enough&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;人与人之间小小的互动就足以&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To contaminate uswithcloseness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让对方染病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Twometresdisappearoverthemeetingofeyes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一旦对视两米的社交距离就会凭空消失&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Or maybe we cannot bear it&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;或许我们无法忍受&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It hurts too much to see and not touch, not hug, not hold&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;见到彼此，却无法碰触，拥抱，握手&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Today I am resolved to look.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今天，我决定去看。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Steve Buissinne on Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第七天：我在天堂过得很好</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a story about a ghost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一个角落，天堂（GPS无法定位）&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A corner of heaven (No GPS signal)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“我是在哪里？”刚刚睡醒的乔揉了揉自己的眼睛，头有点疼，昨晚又喝了太多酒。他睁开疲倦的双眼，环顾四周，发现自己在全然陌生的地方，大概是还没睡醒吧，他决定合上眼睛，再睡一会儿。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Where am I?” Joe has just woken up. He rubs the sleep from his eyes. His head hurts from the drinks the night before. He opens his tired eyes and looks around him to discover he finds himself in a strange place. He must be dreaming still, so he decides to close his eyes and sleep a while longer.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;不知道又过了多久，乔总算是醒了，倦意全无，然而他发现周围的环境依旧很陌生，不是他在莱科沃斯（Lake Worth）的公寓。他究竟是在哪儿？这里很光亮，一切都很干净，也很安静。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After a long while, Joe finally wakes again, this time completely refreshed. His surroundings however are unchanged in their foreignness, this is not his apartment in Lake Worth. Where on earth is he? It is bright here, everything is clean and quiet.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔努力坐起身来，惊讶地发现他好像睡在了云上，突然他感到害怕，他不会摔下去吧？到底发生了什么？为什么他一觉醒来会在这个奇怪的地方？这里没有电脑，没有手机，没有互联网，人影也不见一个。乔用力掐了掐自己的胳膊，还挺疼的，说明他是清醒的。他已经有一年多没磕过药了，不可能会有幻觉的。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe struggles into a sitting position only to make the startling discovery that he seems to have fallen asleep on a cloud. Suddenly he is scared, what if he falls? What is going on? Why has he woken up in this strange place? He doesn’t have his computer, nor his phone, there is no internet. He is completely alone, there are no other humans to be seen. Joe pinches his arm, it hurts. He must be awake. He has been clean for a year, this is not a trip.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;不知又过了多久，有在云上行走的路人见到他，“Howdy, bud!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After another long while, someone approaches him on the clouds. “Howdy, bud!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔惊喜地回了一句，“你好呀！你知道我们在哪吗？&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe, surprised, only replies “Hey! Do you know where we are?”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;路人见怪不怪的样子，“恭喜你上天堂了！”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The passerby seems unfazed. “Congrats for making it to heaven!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔一脸困惑地问：“天堂？”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe is utterly bewildered. “Heaven?”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;路人拍了拍乔的肩膀，“对呀，我们都死了。看开点吧，至少我们没下地狱嘛。”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The stranger pats him on the shoulder. “That’s right, we’re all dead here. Chin up buddy, at least we’re not in hell.”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;又过了大半年，乔慢慢适应了天堂的新生活，挺不错的，过去几年的积攒的脂肪也消耗掉了，恢复到了他曾经引以为傲的健康身材。他偶尔会悄悄看看地上的亲友，默默祝福他们。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Months pass by before Joe starts to get used to his new life in heaven. It’s not bad actually, he’s managed to burn off all the fat built up over the years and is back to the healthy body he used to be so proud of. Sometimes he secretly visits his friends and family and quietly watches over them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;有一天，乔感觉到地上的朋友们在想他，原来今天是他的26岁生日。他想知道想念他的朋友们都在干什么，决定随机看看一个朋友。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;One day, Joe realises that many friends on earth are thinking about him. It is his 26th birthday. He would like to know what they are doing, these friends who miss him. So he picks a train of thought to ride to one of them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;纽卡斯尔，英国&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Newcastle, England&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;苏菲在浏览脸书，犹豫要不要在乔的时间线上留言，祝他生日快乐，毕竟他都不在了，也看不到了。苏菲想起曾经寄过生日卡到美国去给乔，便有点伤感，乔还那么年轻，他的生活才刚刚步入正轨，有新的转机。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sophie is browsing Facebook. Should she leave a message on Joe’s wall, wish him a happy birthday? He’s not there anymore, he won’t see it. Sophie remembers the birthday cards she sent to Joe in America. It makes her sad. Joe was so young, he had just straightened his life out when it decided to throw him for a loop.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;算了，还是不留言了。苏菲合上电脑，双手托着下巴，发着呆，她原本计划明年暑假去美国旅游的，还可以和乔见个面，大家都做了8年的笔友了。唯一一次大家在同一片大陆的时候还是四年半前，但最后因为苏菲要高考，乔在上海一年的交换学习要结束了，大家没有成功会面。那时候，都觉得还年轻，以后还是有很多机会的。万万没想到……&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No, she won’t write anything. Sophie closes her laptop, rests her chin in her hands and lets her mind wander. Next year over the summer, she was going to travel to America, was going to see Joe, her pen pal of 8 years. Four and a half years have passed since they last were on the same continent at the same time. But with Sophie busy preparing for final exams and Joe’s year abroad in Shanghai passing by so quickly, they had missed each other. Back then Sophie was sure they would meet each other someday, they were young after all. How could she have known?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;明天还要上学，她还是早点睡吧。希望乔在另一个世界里会过得很棒啦。那天晚上，苏菲做了一个梦，梦见了红发的乔，他还是和以前一样瘦，乔还和她说，“Don’t worry, I am doing very well in another world.” 苏菲感到欣慰，拥抱了乔，拍了拍他的背，说“I am so glad to know that.” 梦里他们还聊了好久的天，只是苏菲睡醒之后都不记得他们说过什么了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sophie has classes in the morning, so she goes to bed early. She hopes that Joe is happy in another world. That evening, Sophie has a dream. In her dream she sees Joe, with his ginger hair and slim stature. Joe says to her “Don’t worry, I am doing very well in another world.” Sophie is filled with relief, she gives Joe a hug and pats his back. “I am so glad to know that.” They talk for a long time in her dream, but when Sophie wakes up, she doesn’t remember a word.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by skeeze from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 7: Lady of the Castle</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a story about a ghost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I was born during a dreadful winter storm in the servants’ quarters at a great castle. I never met the lords and ladies who belonged upstairs in the satin-stuffed rooms. My mother deemed me too young, too loud, too filthy and so the kitchen was where I spent most of my time. One of the stern-faced men whose portraits now stared us down from in between marble columns had cherished solitude and quiet so much that he had banished the busy kitchen from the castle keep entirely. It had been moved to a cavernous hall underneath a guard tower which was rumoured to have imprisoned in its upper floors many who had disturbed the peace of the lord, amongst them a persistent debt collector sent all the way from London. Stories of these unfortunate souls locked away behind cold stone walls took hold in my head. Tucked into the corner by the firewood, I liked to imagine myself one of them, haunting the castle long after my time. Maybe that is why I stayed behind.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我在一座伟大城堡的佣人居室里出生，当时寒风凛冽。我生前从未见过住在楼上华丽起居室中的贵族家庭。我的母亲嫌我弱小吵闹，太过肮脏，所以我绝大部分的时间都是在厨房度过的。有一位板着脸的领主喜欢独处和宁静，以至于他把忙碌的厨房迁出了主堡。他的画像现在悬挂在大理石柱之间，居高临下地打量着我们。厨房搬到了护卫塔楼底下如同洞穴的厅堂，据说此处曾经关押了许多扰了领主清静的人，有的还是从伦敦远道而来不依不饶的讨债人。我总是记着这些被关押的不幸的灵魂。我蜷缩在壁炉旁的小角落，想象自己也是被关押的人，化作厉鬼在城堡里游荡。或许，这也是我仍留在城堡的原因吧。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I died on a summer day, slipped on the servants’ stairs and there I stood, looking down at myself. It was a shame about the lovely pinafore my mother had sewn for me, now dotted in red. The first decades were torture. I watched my family wither away, saw buildings fall into ruin. I was helpless, all I could do was witness. Then, slowly, a sense of freedom started to seep in. I was now the oldest being in the castle, I had had time enough to explore its dungeons, its hidden staircases, its drafty corridors, its sun-filled sitting rooms. I saw ages pass by, children born, tapestries put up and torn down, lords and ladies circling around in a never-ending dance. I roam the castle still. The kitchen has long since fallen into disrepair, idle travellers now amble down the stairs which once resounded with the frantic feet of maids. I still like to visit the scene of my death from time to time. Open your eyes and see.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;某个夏日里，我在佣人的楼梯滑倒，意外摔死了。我的灵魂出窍，俯视着自己死去的躯壳。母亲为我缝制的洋裙上点满了鲜血，可惜了一条漂亮的裙子。我死后的几十年挺受折磨的，目睹家人的死亡和城堡建筑的衰败。我只能做旁观者，对于发生的一切都无能为力。后来，一种自由的感觉渐渐传来。我现在可是城堡里最古老的存在了，时间充裕，可以自由探索城堡的地牢，隐藏的楼梯密道，冷风穿堂的走廊，以及充满阳光的起居室。我目睹岁月流逝，孩童出生，墙上挂毯的更换，贵族男女无尽的旋转舞步。我依然会在城堡里游荡。曾经玩耍过的厨房早已破败，昔日楼梯间回荡着女仆们匆忙急促的脚步声，而如今充斥着闲来没事的游客。我偶尔还会去我死去的地方看看。睁大你的眼睛，看仔细了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by similitude on Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第六天：一幅画，两棵树</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a painting you find online or on your walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;床头的画中有两颗生长在一起的大树，颜色一深一浅，枝干不多，绿意盎然。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In the painting at the foot of bed there are two trees twisted into each other. One is light, one is dark. Their branches are few in number but rich in green.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;看见树，想到尼采的《查拉图斯特拉如是说》，他写道：“其实人跟树是一样的，越是向往高处的阳光，它的根就越要伸向黑暗的地底”。随着年龄的增长，愈发觉得人总要直视自己的黑暗面，才能让光明的那面更好地生长，也明白单纯不和善良挂钩，人可以有过痛苦的经历，见过世间的残酷，依旧保有纯粹美好的一面，做出充满善意的选择。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The trees remind me of this quote from Nietzsche’s “Thus Spoke Zarathustra”: “But it is the same with man as with the tree. The more he seeks to rise into the height and light, the more vigorously do his roots struggle earthward, downward, into the dark, the deep.” The older I grow, the more I discover that to help your brightness develop, you must first look at your darkness. I understand that good isn’t always simple. People with painful experiences who have witnessed the world’s cruelty still have a purely beautiful side. They can still make the right choice.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;人真的很像树，可以立于土地之上，双脚如同树根，感受着大地给予的能量，体验着宇宙和世界的养分。像树一样扎根地上，让人感到很安心呀。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;People are really a lot like trees. When we stand on the ground, our feet become roots connected to the earth’s energy. We are nourished by the energy of the universe, of our planet. Planting our roots into the ground sets the mind at ease.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Painting by Klaus Rathgen.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 6: Nu Dans un Intérieur</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a painting you find online or on your walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This morning I woke up feeling fluffy inside and out. The soft pillow against my cheek, the aftereffects of a generous helping of vino. My nose was the first thing to spring into action. The faint smell of coffee drifting in from somewhere carried promise. I sat up in bed, slowly to not upset the cotton filling my head.  I carefully made my way over to the blinds, took a deep breath and threw them wide open. Light flooded the orange walls, danced over the painted flowers. Taking in the jubilantly blue sky, the clouds around my temples seemed to begin to clear.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今早起床，我感觉整个人都轻飘飘。我的脸靠在柔软的枕头上，这是葡萄酒喝多了的结果。我的鼻子最早苏醒，闻到了咖啡的淡香味。我坐在床上，缓慢起身，不想太过头晕，我小心地越过床前的屏风，深吸一口气，果断把屏风拉开。光线照射到橘色的墙壁上，映照着墙上的花。窗外的蓝天令人心旷神怡，太阳穴旁的白云似乎在散去。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I turned the shower to scalding heat and simply stood there, feeling my body finally shake off the last bits of fuzziness. I didn’t bother putting on a gown. Outside the window I could see nothing but blue, and the anonymity of a tourist shrouded me. I fixed my hair, brushed my teeth, secure in the knowledge that even if someone caught a glimpse of me, they would have no way of connecting this body to a real person. I would just be that to them, a nude study, a still image, a flash of skin.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我调好水温，淋着滚烫的洗澡水，感受着身体最后一丝疲倦的褪去。我懒得穿上浴袍。我只见窗外的蓝，我的游客身份保护了我。我整理完头发，刷完牙，确认即便有人看见我，他们也无法联想到我是谁。他们只会把我当作一具裸体，一幅静物画，一副皮囊。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I laid out my clothes on the bed, shields for my trip to the source of the still-wafting smell. The blue dress it would have to be, the sky called for it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我把衣物置于床上，准备换好衣服去喝咖啡。我一定会穿上蓝裙子，好搭配今日的蓝天。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Painting by Pierre Bonnard.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第五天：小鹿的樱花梦</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/ -&lt;p&gt;Go outside. Put on your writer hat. Try to notice 5 things to write about!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;小鹿和家人在田野里悠转，享受温暖和煦的阳光，吃着田间植被与落叶。明天要转夏令时了，小鹿兴奋地期待着，春天来了，天气应该会更舒服吧。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The little deer treaded lightly on the field, basking in the warm sunlight, grazing on plants and fallen leaves. It was the day before summer time and the little deer was excited. Spring was coming and with it the warmer temperatures it liked.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;最近的气温足够暖和，迎来了初春的花期，花树开始初吐芬芳，其中包括小鹿最喜欢的樱花树了。田野附近的樱花树已是娇艳盛开，每一朵小巧的樱花都微不足道，但仔细观看，层层重瓣繁复华丽。满树樱花蔚为观止，小鹿忍不住想象再过些时日，如若起风，樱花随风飘舞，如同落雪的美丽。啊，到时它可以在堆在地上的柔软落花里打滚，沾染樱花浅淡的馨香，亦或是把自己埋在花堆里，把陨落质柔的花瓣当作棉被，抵挡初春的清寒，它还可以尝尝樱花滋味，毕竟平时吃的都是绿色植被，难得有粉色的食材可用……&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The mild air had already blown in the first flowers of early spring. Plants were sprouting their first buds, amongst them the little deer’s favourite, the cherry trees. Next to the field stood a cherry in full bloom already. Its tiny delicate blossoms looked insignificant from a distance, but close up they revealed a luxurious abundance of petals, layer upon layer. The little deer stood admiring the tree. It imagined that in a few weeks, when the wind started blowing, it would take the petals with it and cover the ground in cherry snow. Oh, how nice it would be to roll around in the piled-up petals, to imprint their scent onto its fur. Or to bury itself under the soft cover of fallen blossoms and hide from the cold spells of early spring. And then to savour the petals’ taste would add a welcome dash of pink to its ever-green diet.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“看，那里有鹿！”小鹿闻声，抬头望向把它从樱花梦中吵醒的人，噢，原来是骑车的小贝。小贝又补充道，“看到了那几只吗？就在田里面。”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Look, there’s deer over there!” heard the deer suddenly. It raised its head to make out the one who had disturbed its cherry dreams. Ah, it was Johanna on a bicycle. “Did you see them? In the field!”, she added.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“看到了！”骑车跟在小贝身后的筱然回答。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“I did!”, said Sophie, cycling behind Johanna.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;小贝数了数，“有四只鹿！你可以当作是路上见到的四样东西。”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johanna counted. “There’s four of them! There you go, that’s four things for your story.”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“太好啦，”筱然感叹，“那就好写多了！”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Perfect,” Sophie exclaimed. “That’ll make it so much easier to write!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;小鹿远远地看着两人骑车远去，继续沉浸在初日芳华的美好之中。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The little deer watched them cycle away into the distance and let itself sink back into the beauty of an awakening spring.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by dewdrop157 from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 5: Adventure Kitty</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Go outside. Put on your writer hat. Try to notice 5 things to write about! What I saw: a family having a barbecue, a butterfly pacing me on my run, a front yard full of purple hyacinths and yellow primroses, a tree hung with Easter eggs, and an adventurous cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我看到了：在烧烤的一家人，和我一起慢跑的蝴蝶，布满紫色风信子和鹅黄色樱草的前院，挂上复活节彩蛋的树 ，以及一只爱冒险的小猫咪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The breeze tickles my whiskers and I am awake. First things first, I give my body a delicious stretch. The sun warms the tips of my ears, a bumblebee buzzes through the shimmering air. Then my nose detects something wonderful. Meat on hot coals.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;微风轻挠我脸上的须，我是一只醒着的小猫。首先，我要活动下筋骨。阳光照得我耳尖暖烘烘的，一只黄蜂在晒得眩晕的空气中嗡嗡叫。我好像嗅到了什么美味，那是热碳烤肉。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The next garden is full of colour and noise. I slink around the fence, stay low to the ground. Maybe if I’m fast enough I can scavenge a scrap of meat from a plate abandoned to play. The humans and their many noises used to scare me, but I know now they mean nothing by them. They are just bad at quiet. There I spot it! Beneath the table, carelessly dropped. I pounce, bite and run, elated by my catch. I chew the juicy meat with relish.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我来到了另一户人家的花园，缤纷喧闹。我绕着栅栏不紧不慢地行走，没有一丝声响。小孩子吃烤肉吃到一半跑去玩，如果我跑得快，说不准还能捡到一块吃剩的烤肉。我平时挺怕人的，也怕他们的动静声响。不过我发现人类的声响没有特别的意思，他们只是不知道怎么安静下来。我发现了一块烤肉！就在桌底下，不小心弄掉的。我跳起来去叼肉，随即逃跑，兴奋不已。我嚼着的多汁烤肉，非常满意。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Next to me suddenly a flash of yellow. It dances up and down, back and forth. A butterfly has come to keep me company. It dashes ahead and I break into a run. Eyes fixed on the bouncing body, my feet fly over cracks in the concrete. My legs are my wings and I tango with my flighty friend.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一抹黄影飞来我身旁，四处转动，来来回回的。原来是一只蝴蝶来陪我玩耍。我追着朝前飞舞的蝴蝶，紧盯着它摇曳的翅膀，越过了水泥地板上的缝隙。我的小猫腿如同蝴蝶的翅膀，让我随着会飞的蝴蝶朋友翩翩起舞。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Then a roar. My instincts take over and I bolt to cover. Cowered underneath a car, I turn my ears to the sound, which has morphed into a steady grumble. My heart beats wildly against my chest. I inch forwards in my hiding spot, until I can make out the garden across the street. There the butterfly still dances, now around a human pushing something in front of him. Slowly my body relaxes, and I notice a new scent. Wet grass, freshly torn from the stem. I will never get used to these howling monsters the humans keep with them, but I am glad for my fluttering friend and its serenity.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我听见一声巨响。猫咪的本能让我迅速躲到车底，抬起耳朵，注意着外界的声响，那声巨响逐渐变成平稳的嘟囔。我感受到急促的心跳。我从藏身的车底往外看，慢慢往外走，直到对面街道的花园越来越清晰。那只蝴蝶依旧起舞，只不过它现在是在一个人类跟前飞舞着。我缓缓歇息，还嗅到一种不一样的清香，是湿润小草断掉之后的味道。我一向不习惯人类这些机器的噪音，但是我为蝴蝶朋友感到高兴，因为它感觉不到这样的噪音。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I dare not move closer to the noise, so I slip into the garden behind me. Here the green grass is dotted in purple and yellow and the air is sweet. I place my paws gingerly between the dots, protecting the fragile sprouts of life around me. This is a good place to rest. Up ahead I see a tree, its twisting branches still bare, but decorated with eggs on strings in all colours of the rainbow. A fork high up in the branches is perfectly cat-shaped, I propel myself up the tree and curl up against the warm bark. As I drift off into sleep, I see a streak of yellow beside me and feel six tiny feet touch down on my nose.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我不敢走近传来噪音的地方，我只敢悄悄走进身后的花园，翠绿的草坪上零星布满黄色紫色的小花，就连空气也是香甜的。我的爪子落在小花之间，小心护着周遭脆弱的生灵。这是休息的好地方，抬头见一树木，枝干缠绕，未见叶子，但却挂上了色彩缤纷的复活节彩蛋。树枝上还挂了一把叉子，大小恰好适宜让一只小猫躺下，我爬上树干，卷起身子，靠着暖和的树干。我快进入梦乡时，迷糊中看到一抹黄颜色，只觉有六只小小的脚丫落在我的鼻子上。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Kessa from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 