<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quarantine Chronicles</title>
    <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Quarantine Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://johannabernatzky.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 4: Charlie&#39;s Secret</title>
        <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a secret you or a character have been keeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlie was still giggling when she unlocked the front door. Jess had been so funny, imitating Mr Hobbs, their maths teacher. “How many times do I have to tell you, right angles are per-pen-dicular!” She had a way of getting it just right, the way he spat out his p’s, like he wanted to slingshot them straight into your brain. “Repeat after me Charlie, pa-per, pers-piration, per-plexed, pep-per…”
Pur-ple pa-prika Charlie thought as she walked down the corridor, that’s a good one. Pep-peroni pizza. “How was your day honey?”, her mother shouted from the kitchen, “still hungry?” “I ate at Jess’,” Charlie replied, already halfway up the stairs. Going into the kitchen at this hour was dangerous. She loved her parents in the morning, she really did. But in the evening, they were a complete disaster. All they wanted to do was talk. It would start with “anything interesting happen at school today?” and wouldn’t end before they hadn’t extracted from her every minute detail of her day. She supposed old people needed the entertainment. Her parents both worked at the city library. They woke up together, had breakfast (her father made the tea, her mother the porridge), went to work together and walked home together. Sometimes it seemed to her like over all their years together, always together, they had forgotten how to talk to each other.&lt;br&gt;
Tonight, Charlie didn’t feel like stepping in for their entertainment. She didn’t want her day dissected until it didn’t feel whole anymore. It had been too precious. And she was worried. Worried that her parents would notice something in the way she spoke about Jess. Worried that they could see the butterflies tickling her insides whenever she thought about her. She so desperately wanted to keep them secret, keep them safe. In Biology they had learned that butterfly wings were so fragile that one touch, one raindrop might be enough to break them. So she knew she couldn’t let them out, couldn’t let her parents see. 
She closed her door tightly behind her. On her desk sat a plate of cookies, steaming still from the oven. Sometimes her parents weren’t too bad she supposed. Her pocket pinged. 
Jess: What are you up to?
Charlie: Just thinking about butterflies. You?
Jess: Haha really? You know I used to collect butterflies, seems sadistic in hindsight though.
Charlie: You preposterous person…Mr Hobbs is disappointed in you.
Jess: I know, I’ll personally apologise to him tomorrow.
Charlie took a bite of her cookie and felt a warmth spreading throughout her. It really was sadistic she thought to herself, keeping butterflies locked up. One day she would let them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Johanna.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第三天：今天的挑战</title>
        <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-26/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-26/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-26/ -&lt;p&gt;Set your text to white and try freewriting in invisible mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今天的新挑战，把字体颜色调成白色进行记录，无法看到自己打的是什么字，总之就这样一直码字码下去，但是偶尔出现的蓝色红色波浪线像是举着牌子表示这里有点可疑！&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Today’s challenge is to set your font to white and type. This way you can’t see what you’re typing, letter after letter you put in, only the odd blue and red line pops up like a warning sign, you’ve typed something suspicious here!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;有一部日本动画《工作细胞》讲述了人类身体里面运作的各类细胞，这部动画以一种很可爱的方式给我们科普。里面的细胞形象都非常可爱。原来人体里面有那么多的细胞在努力工作，我们的身体才能够好好的运作。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Cells at Work” is an anime series about the work all the little cells in our bodies do. A cutesified scientific education. All the cells in it are adorable. All these cells in our bodies have to work hard for our bodies to run smoothly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;记得有次朋友说，“看到那些细胞这么努力，会特别想要好好的爱护自己。剧集里面，人的身体出现些小小的问题，不小心划破皮，里面的细胞们仿佛都处于一种遇到极端自然灾害一样，努力地在细菌入侵的，有些破损的世界里活下来，然后好好重建家园。原来自己能够活着是需要那么多的支持呀。有种自己并不孤独的感觉，想要和大家（细胞们）一起加油，好好地生活！”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A friend once said to me, “Seeing all these cells work hard for me makes me want to take care of myself. It might only be a small problem for a human, a little scratch for example, but for the cells in the show it’s a natural disaster. They have to survive bacteria attacks and world-shattering destruction, and then rebuild their home. And all this just for a human to live. It makes me feel like I’m not alone, like I want to join forces with them and live a good life!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今天也不知怎么突然就想起了这部动画片，想和大家分享。其实我白天还在读张爱玲的散文随笔，和这部动画片并没有太大的关系呢。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Today I thought about this anime and wanted to share it with everybody. I was reading Zhang Eileen’s essays earlier, but they don’t really have anything in common with this cartoon.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;这两天小贝很认真地把我们的博客做好了，记录21世纪第三个十年的开端的，一场疫情下的生活。我们的生活也因为这突如其来的新冠病毒发生了改变：更加谨慎的卫生习惯，前所未有的居家隔离，和保持两米的社交距离。不知道若干年后，未来的世代某天翻到我们的博客，读到我们写和译的内容会是什么样的感受呢？2020年开年的三个多月以来，我多次体会到“世事难料”，放两个月前，我完全不会想象到之后自己会在安静的德国乡村里和好友一家过着预设隔绝的隔离生活，但问题不大，日子还是很开心的。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johanna has been working hard on our blog to report on our lives under quarantine at the outset of the third decade of the 21st century. Our lives have turned upside down because of this new virus: stricter hygiene measures, unprecedented isolation at home, two metres of social distance. I wonder what people will think if they discover our blog years into the future. These first three months of 2020 have been full of didn’t see that comings. Two months ago I couldn’t have imagined I would be here in this quiet German village in complete isolation with my friend and her family. It’s no problem though, life is good.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by allinonemovie from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-26/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第三天：她的秘密</title>
        <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a secret you or a character have been keeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;丽塔是一个普通的高中生，平时就忙着读书考试，偶尔写写日记，最期待的就是周末和放假。她有一个小秘密，自13岁生日以后，她能够在睡梦中穿越回古代。两年的时光旅行者睡梦生涯让丽塔很有动力去查阅史料，了解不同的风俗和学习新的语言。她也不知道梦究竟会把她带到何处，好在时光穿梭梦像电视连续剧，一个故事完结才进入下一个故事。目前为止，她已经到过平安时代的日本和盛唐时期的中国。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rita was an ordinary high school student, usually busy with studying and exams. She kept a diary and she loved weekends and school breaks above anything else. But she had a secret. When she was 13, she started travelling back in time in her dreams. Two years of dream time-travelling had spurred her on to dig out historical sources, discover past customs and learn new languages. Although she could never be sure where her dreams would take her, they helpfully played out like episodes of a TV series. She only moved on somewhere new after she had completed a story arc. In her dreams she had already visited Heian period Japan and China in its Golden Age, the Tang dynasty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;昨晚梦里丽塔又开始了一段全新的冒险，她在迷糊的睡梦中到达了静寂的小山村附近，抬眼望去，除了碧蓝的天空外，还可见到高耸入云的雪山。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Last night, Rita’s dreams took her on a new adventure. Emerging from indistinct blurs, she found herself outside a quiet village surrounded by mountains. Looking up she saw the blue sky stretching over her head, and below it cloudy peaks capped in white.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;睡醒的丽塔来到书桌旁，翻开日记本，记录起梦中的见闻：&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As soon as she woke up, Rita opened her diary at her desk and wrote down what she had seen:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;梦里到了不知在哪儿的小山村，附近有漂亮的雪山，天气很好，日照时间很长，应该是在高纬度地区吧。周围村民讲什么我都听不懂，他们都是白人，穿着当地的传统服饰，见到我都很惊讶，盯着我看，弄到我都不好意思了，还好他们没把我抓起来拷问。他们也许从来没有见过长相异域的东方人吧。村里有一座教堂，有圆圆的拱顶，应该是东正教堂吧。那我猜测，梦里的地方应该是在东欧吧。后来，有一个金发碧眼的可爱女孩子来和我搭讪，她和我年龄相仿。我听不懂她说什么，但是凭借肢体语言和各种比划，我们好像可以交流一下，她的名字听起来是Elena… …或许我今天放学之后需要上网搜索一下有关东欧的资料吧，至少查一下有什么文化禁忌，不要冒犯到当地人。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Last night, I went to a village in the mountains, I don’t know where. The peaks were snowy. The weather was good and the sun stayed up for a long time. A high latitude probably. I couldn’t understand a word the locals were saying. They were all white and seemed to be wearing traditional clothes. They were are all shocked to see me and kept throwing glances at me. It was lucky I made it out without them forcing me into a cross-examination. They’ve probably never seen an Asian like me. At some point, a little girl with blonde hair and green eyes came up to talk to me, she seemed to be my age. Even though I didn’t know what she was saying, we could communicate a little bit with our hands and feet. Her name sounds like Elena. Maybe after school today I’ll do some research on Eastern Europe, at least I should know what the taboos are, don’t want to get on the locals’ bad side.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;丽塔记录完梦里的内容便合上日记本，换好校服，洗漱干净，背上书包，出门上学。虽然她有不为人知的冒险旅途，但至少表面上看，她还是一个普通得不能在普通的高中生了，还是要好好读书，参加高考的普通15岁女生。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After finishing her entry, Rita shut her diary, put on her school uniform, had a wash, picked up her backpack and left for school. And even if she had just been on an extraordinary adventure, from the outside she still looked like an ordinary 15-year-old high school student studying hard for her exams.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by simplyelke from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 3: The Cursor&#39;s Lament</title>
        <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/26-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/26-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/26-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Set your text to white and try freewriting in invisible mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Where am I? Everything is bright, I have forgotten my past, I don’t know my future. All I have is now, an existence barely there. I am flickering in and out of consciousness. I feel something. A rhythm is driving me forwards. In and out and in and out. What am I running towards? My path leaves a squiggly line in the whiteness. It dances with me, closer closer closer and&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我到底身在何处？一切都如此刺眼，我不记得过往，前路未知。我只有当下，又几乎不存在 。我一直闪烁，没有意识。我有一些感觉，驱使我向前的节奏。飘忽不定。我向前的目标是什么？我在白色之处走过，留下曲折，不同寻常的痕迹。它和我一同舞动，近一点，更近一点，然后……&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gone. Loneliness is a freeing thing. It has given me wings to soar, faster than I ever did before. What does it matter if I have no goal? I make my own pace, I light up your screen.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;消失。孤独实际是无拘无束的，赋予我飞翔的翅膀，让我飞得更快。即使我毫无目标，又如何呢？我有适合自己的步伐，我点亮了你的屏幕。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Where am I going? I’ve left you a present, a painting almost. What does it look like to you? A sunset? Maybe a face? So many things look like faces if you try hard enough.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我在去往何方？我已经给予你一份礼物，几乎是一副画作。你觉得它像什么？夕照？或许一张脸？如果你仔细看看，会发现许多像人脸的地方。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I worry my story will have no end as it has no beginning. Remember me today.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我担心我的故事没有结局，正如它没有开始一样。请记住今天的我。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Johanna.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/26-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第二天：网红熊猫的诞生</title>
        <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-25/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 18:01:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-25/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-25/ -&lt;p&gt;Pick 5 words at random from different blog posts, tweets, or articles and use them all in a scene. 熊猫、烦躁、郁金香、早饭、月球. Panda, annoyed, tulip, breakfast, moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;胖达是一只毛茸茸的熊猫，她生活在文化多元的伦敦。胖达偶尔不是那么有耐心，一旦要排队挤地铁，她就会有点烦躁。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In the cultured city of London lives a cuddly panda. She goes by Panda. A bit impatient, queuing for the tube often annoys her.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;胖达在伦敦最大的动物园工作，一到动物园她就会和其他员工一样打卡签到。与其他工作人员不同的是，签到之后，胖达就会进入到熊猫馆，在那里待上大半天。她的工作就是向人们展示普通熊猫的生活，在熊猫馆里面和其他熊猫朋友嬉戏打闹，啃啃竹子，吃吃水果，玩累了就睡个觉，到了下班时间就离馆回家。然而，胖达偶尔有些小郁闷，担心在动物园里向人类展示的熊猫生活会加深人们对熊猫的刻板印象，因为在现代社会里，熊猫除了吃喝玩乐，享受生活之外，还是有很多追求的，而胖达无法在动物园里展示熊猫生活的另一面。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Panda works in the biggest zoo in London. When she arrives for work, she swipes in just like her co-workers. But unlike them, after swiping in she makes a beeline for the panda pavilion where she spends her day. Her job is to show visitors a panda’s daily life. She plays around with her panda friends inside the enclosure, she chews on bambus, munches on fruit and takes naps when she’s exhausted. When the zoo closes, she says goodbye to the enclosure and goes home. Sometimes Panda gets a little worried that her work at the zoo only solidifies people’s misconceptions. In reality, besides the simple pleasures of eating and playing, pandas nowadays have their own dreams. But from within the enclosure, Panda has no way of making them see.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;胖达吃早饭时有一个新想法，就是去开一个Instagram账号，发布一些真正的熊猫生活动态，让更多人了解真实的熊猫生活，改变人们对熊猫的刻板印象。毕竟全世界有那么多人喜欢毛茸茸的熊猫，也愿意花钱到动物园里围观他们嘛！胖达开始认真计划要发布什么内容，写什么样的文案，与粉丝们分享一些什么样的心得。胖达想到未来自己可能会成为网红，拥有更大的影响力，那到时候她说不准能够实现小时候的心愿—成为一位服装设计师，设计和发布含有熊猫元素的服饰。啊，说不准未来还会有人为她拍摄专门的纪录片呢！啊，说不定她能靠Instagram发家致富呢！等有钱之后，胖达还可以实现她去月球度假的小心愿呢！胖达越想越激动，便马上申请了一个新的Instagram账号，名为Miss Panda，并决定使用中英文同时更新。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;One day over breakfast, Panda has an idea. Why not open an Instagram account to share the true life of a panda? Once people see what pandas truly get up to, surely they will understand. These masses of people who flood to the zoos to see their beloved fluffy pandas, they will want to learn. So Panda starts to plan out her posts, writes out captions, lays out what she wants to share with her fans. Maybe one day she will become an influencer, an online celebrity! Maybe she will finally become a fashion designer like she has always dreamed, bring her panda-inspired designs to life! Maybe one day she will feature in a documentary! Maybe Instagram will make her rich! Rich enough to travel to the moon even! Taken by a wave of excitement, Panda immediately signs up to Instagram: Miss Panda is born, an account run in both Chinese and English.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;第一条贴文发布什么好呢？胖达一边吃着吐司，一边沉思。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;What should her first post be? Panda deliberates over toast.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;春天快到了，荷兰的郁金香应该也开了，那她不如到郁金香花田里拍摄一组春天主题的照片，应该会很可爱的。今年欧洲各国都颁布了旅游禁令，荷兰估计是去不成了，但问题不大。胖达去年到过荷兰的郁金香花田，也拍了许多满意的照片，那就用去年的照片吧。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It will be spring soon, the tulips will be blooming in Holland. So why not visit the tulip fields for a photo shoot? It will make for an adorable scene. But no, the entirety of Europe is under a travel ban, Holland included. Panda is quick on her paws, remembering she still has pictures from last year’s tulip trip to Holland. She will just use one of them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020年3月25日，熊猫第一网红胖达女士发布了第一条Instagram贴文，从此开启了她的网红生涯。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;On the 25th of March 2020, Miss Panda publishes her first Instagram post. A star is born.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Cimberley from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-25/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 2: Behind the Waterfall</title>
        <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/25-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/25-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/25-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Pick 5 words at random from different blog posts, tweets, or articles and use them all in a scene. Social distance, tourist attraction, currywurst, cherry blossoms, virtual kiss. 个人空间、景点、咖喱香肠、樱花、隔空亲吻.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deep in the mountains, hidden behind a gurgling waterfall, lies a secret land. Only the rarest souls find its entrance. Hikers marvel at the refreshing mist, check a tourist attraction off their list, send their loved ones photographic evidence. #nature #missingyou #virtualkiss. They come in groups, in pairs, with their families, and leave, propelled down the mountain by their desire for a drink, a currywurst with chips, or a soft cushion and the crackle of a fireplace.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;深山里，流水瀑布后，隐藏着一片秘境，其入口鲜为人知。登山者感叹水雾的清新，将此景点在旅行清单上划去，给亲朋好友发送这里的照片，证明自己可是来过这里的。他们将照片传到社交媒体上，标上#亲近自然 #想念你 #隔空亲吻 的话题。来这的游人通常是三五成群，成双成对，与家人出行，来来去去，匆忙下山，只为一杯饮料，一份咖喱香肠和薯条，或是坐在柔软的沙发上，享受壁炉火焰传来的温暖。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;But every once in a while, hikers travel up the path alone. They carry melancholy in their hearts, the world has become heavy for them. They let bird song fill their heads and silence the noise. They seek not inclusion, not pity, they long only for social distance. These hikers may find themselves pulled towards the gush of water, cherishing the biting cold that drives out all thought. And showered in glacial droplets, they may feel a tug at the back of their coat. A soothing stroke of their shoulder. A sudden warm breeze, a light that sets the water curtain ablaze.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;偶尔也会有独行的登山者前来，他们惆怅郁结，心情沉重。他们聆听鸟儿歌唱，摆脱俗世的嘈杂。他们不求融入人群，不需同情，只是想保有自己的个人空间。这些登山客在不知不觉中走到了瀑布前，他们倍感珍惜冲走了沉重思绪的清冷山水。他们感觉到空气里湿润冰冷的水珠，仿佛有什么东西触碰到他们的外衣，轻推了他们的肩膀。一股突如其来的温暖微风，一束光，让水帘变得闪闪发光。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;What they find in the caves nobody knows. Some return in time for the sunset, some are declared missing only to be found one day, wandering a path they have long since forgotten. Memories of their time behind the waterfall vanish the moment they reemerge. What remains is a faint scent of cherry blossoms, the warmth of a summer day and a lightness of the soul.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;无人知晓登山者在山洞里的见闻。有的登山者在日落之前归去，有的则是在秘境中呆的太久，以至于别人都以为他们失踪了，而他们也不记得自己还是如何来到瀑布后的秘境，也不记得在秘境的经历，唯有樱花的微微馨香，夏日的暖意和灵魂深处的轻松犹存。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Lars Nissen from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/25-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第一天：闭门保命的日子</title>
        <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-24/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:30:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-24/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-24/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a character who&#39;s stuck inside. How do they feel about it? Why are they there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;近日，一种丧尸病毒席卷欧洲，活人若是遭到丧尸啃咬，轻则收点皮肉伤，加以治疗，仍能恢复过上正常生活，重则失去自由意志，成为胡乱咬人丧尸部队一员。为了群众避免无辜受伤，各国政府进入紧急状态，宣布宵禁措施，限制公民活动。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A zombie virus is spreading around Europe. A bite that only barely breaks the skin can be treated and the victims continue their lives as before, the severe bites however bleed out a person’s free will and force them into the ranks of ravaging zombies. To protect their people from harm, governments have called out a state of emergency and put their citizens on lockdown.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;但说来也奇怪，所谓“一物降一物”。丧尸病毒纵然可怕，但也是有克星的——它们极度害怕绿色蔬菜。据说，有位菜农在送菜时遭遇一群丧尸袭击，幸好他车上的绿菜多，吓得死亡大队仓皇而逃。此事一上新闻，便引发了绿色蔬菜的抢购热潮，如今超市里可是一菜难求。买不到菜怎么办？&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;But as paper beats rock, rock beats scissors and scissors beats paper, the zombies are not invincible. In all their horror, they have a weakness – they wither at the sight of green vegetables. It is rumoured that a farmer ambushed by zombies on a delivery run showed his attackers a sight of his truck full of greens imposing enough to scatter them to the four winds. As this became public knowledge, a stockpiling frenzy set in, clearing supermarket shelves clean of any trace of green.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;求生欲总会驱使人自己种菜保命，凯丽就是买不到菜的人，她只能躲在家里自己种菜保命。绿色蔬菜的生长周期也不短，但好在她前几天在园艺商店里买到了几盆已经发芽的白菜苗，再加上凯丽一个月前开始尝试种植沙拉菜，目前她的菜苗数量充裕，若非到规模庞大的丧尸队伍，她的小菜苗是能够保护她的。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Survival instinct still drives people, those who can grow their own vegetables for protection. Not having been able to buy any vegetables, Kelly has locked herself in at home and is growing her own. Green vegetables take their time to grow, but Kelly still has freshly sprouting cabbage seedlings from the gardening centre, and a month ago she planted her first salad seeds. She has enough vegetable shoots and seedlings to last her through an attack, provided she is not overrun by a hoard.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;凯丽盯着花园中的一盆盆嫩绿小菜苗，思绪万千，没想到她这么爱往外跑的一个人，竟快一个月未出过门了，全是靠着去年“黑五”打折，不小心按错数量，购入的20袋意大利面存活下来的。过去一个月，她利用家中能用的一切食材，努力尝试新的食谱，为在家躲避灾难的独居生活增添一丝光彩。凯丽心中感叹，这场灾难结束后，她可是好几个月都不想再吃意粉了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In her garden, Kelly stands and watches over the rows of translucent green seedlings. She hasn’t left her home in almost a month, she who so loved to go on adventures. For sustenance she only has the 20 packs of spaghetti she accidentally added to her cart last year on Black Friday. For a month now, she has used all the ingredients she could find in her home, combining them into new recipes for a little splash of colour in her solitary confinement. Kelly sighs. After this is all over, she will give spaghetti a wide berth for a few months.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Jill Wellington from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-24/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 1: But Why Can&#39;t I Go Out?</title>
        <link>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/24-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/24-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/24-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a character who&#39;s stuck inside. How do they feel about it? Why are they there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“But why can’t I go out mum?” asked the little meerkat. It was barely a few weeks old, silver fluff still covered its fur like cobwebs. A meerkat’s favourite place to be is in the scorching sun. Coming out from the dark tunnels with their twists and turns, the eyes take a while to adjust. Then like a sudden sunrise, the world appears shimmering golden. The little meerkat usually took a while longer to adjust its eyes, then darted after its sister. Together they explored the desert, hiding behind dry logs, jumping over rocks and chasing each other’s shadows.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“妈妈，为什么我不能出门呀？”小狐獴问。这只小狐獴不过刚出生几周，银色的绒毛像是罩在身上的蜘蛛网一样。狐獴最喜欢晒太阳，他们通常会穿过阴暗似迷宫的地道，爬上地面，总要过一会儿眼睛才能适应外面的光线，如同突如其来的日出，外边的世界散发着金光。这只小狐獴通常要花更长的时间让适应光线，再迅速跟着姐姐。他们一同在沙漠探索，藏身于枯木，在岩石上蹦跶，追逐彼此的影子。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Why can’t I go out mum?” The meerkat nudged its mother. It could barely see her, but nuzzled against her side, it could feel her tense her muscles. Crouched down, the mother’s body quivered, her ears laid back, her head turning quickly. Suddenly, a loud screech pierced the dark silence. The mother jolted and pushed the little meerkat behind her. Hidden in the cold burrow, the meerkat was not afraid. It did not yet understand the sharp claws of an eagle, the hot viscosity of blood. Its large eyes betrayed nothing but curiosity. It longed to escape the monotony of the tunnel and bask again in the glorious heat.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“妈妈，为什么我不能出门呀？”小狐獴继续缠着妈妈。其实小狐獴也看不清妈妈，但还是往她身上蹭蹭，感觉妈妈的肌肉紧绷。狐獴妈妈开始打颤，蜷缩身体，耳朵后缩，马上转过头来。忽然间，一声刺耳的巨响划破了黑暗中的寂静。狐獴妈妈极速将孩子护在身后。躲在冰冷地洞里的小狐獴未有丝毫惊恐，他还不知道若被老鹰锋利的爪子一抓，粘稠的鲜血便喷涌而出。小狐獴瞪大好奇的眼睛，他一直想要逃离枯燥乏味的地道，再次回到灿烂的阳光底下。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Can I go out mum?” the little meerkat asked once more, this time knowing it was to no avail. The way out was blocked, the mother’s ears deaf to her children. Restless, the little meerkat turned its head, squinting into the darkness for its sister. But the darkness was lifting. A light was coming towards the meerkat, growing ever bigger. Already it could make out her sister, further down the tunnel, eyes transfixed by the dancing brightness. As if connected by a thread, the two meerkats began moving towards the light. A shape was forming from the glow, a thing with brittle wings holding up a bulb of a body. The little meerkat had never seen such a creature before, tumbling through the air and lighting up the space around it. Suddenly the winged light seemed to startle at the sight of the meerkat children, rushing back into the dark depths.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“妈妈，我能出门吗？”小狐獴又问了一遍，即便他心知没啥出门的希望了。狐獴妈妈听不见孩子们的声音，而通往外界的路又堵住了。小狐獴莽撞地转头，企图在黑暗中找到自己的姐姐。然而，此时黑暗之中传来一丝亮光。那一点小小的光亮朝着小狐獴飞来，愈发清晰。借着光，小狐獴看到在隧道深处的姐姐。她也目不转睛地盯着跳跃的小光亮。两只小狐獴被那小不点亮光吸引过去，它散发着光芒，有着小小的翅膀。小狐獴从未见过这样的生物，在空中悬着，点亮黑暗。突然，这只小东西被两只小狐獴吓到了，赶紧往黑暗的地洞里飞。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The two meerkats threw each other a glance and then bolted down the tunnel in pursuit. The air rushed past their ears, blood pumping loudly. The faint afterglow led them along, glittering diamonds lit up the walls beside them. Deeper and deeper they went into the earth, until finally the chase slowed. The spectre of light had exhausted its fragile body. The two meerkats found it resting on a rock, its body flickering in and out of consciousness. The little meerkat glanced at its sister. “We have to bring it out,” it finally said.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;两只狐獴对视一番，马上跟着往地道里飞奔，风声在耳旁呼啸，全身都非常紧张。他们紧随那团微弱的光，而钻石将那团小光折射到了墙壁上，熠熠生辉。他们不断地往洞里钻，直到那只小可怜累了飞不动了，躺在石头上歇息，不断颤抖，没有意识。小狐獴看了看姐姐，最后说，“我们要把它送出去。”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The meerkat reached out its paw, slowly, slowly, picked up the dying light and placed it gingerly on top of its sister’s head. The way back was long. In the intermittent glow emanating from between its sister’s ears, the little meerkat could see tunnels upon tunnels branching off into the earth. From some of them smells of berries and herbs wound their way out, some of them resounded with scuffling feet. Some of them were black like a tree struck by lightning, some eagerly reflected the passing light. They all felt like adventure, like a promise to be fulfilled.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;小狐獴慢慢，慢慢地伸出小爪子，捡起那束快要熄灭的光芒，小心翼翼地将它安放在姐姐的头上。回到地面的路很漫长。狐獴姐姐头顶上的那点小小的光照亮了前路，让小狐獴看清了错综复杂的地下隧道。他们经过有梅子和香草气味的地道，也听到自己在某一段路途中的脚步声。有一部分的路漆黑一片，犹如被闪电劈断的树木；还有的路反射着微弱的光线。两只狐獴宝宝觉得这段路就是奇妙的探险，像是被实现的心愿。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As the meerkats walked, the glow grew stronger and stronger. When finally the familiar curve of their mother’s back appeared in front of them, the light hugged each golden hair and sparked off her anxious eyes turning towards her children. She had waited out the danger outside, then had turned her attention back towards them only to discover them gone. Relief washed over her as they appeared, protected as it seemed in a cocoon of light. As soon as they were in reach, she pulled them close into her side and let their scent wash over her.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;狐獴继续向前行走，光线也愈发强烈。最终，他们发现妈妈熟悉的背影，明亮的光线触碰到妈妈金黄的皮毛，让焦虑的妈妈看到自己的孩子们。狐獴妈妈在外面危险结束以后，才发现孩子不见了。现在孩子们都回来了，狐獴妈妈顿时松了一口气。狐獴妈妈抱过走到跟前的孩子们，让自己沾满孩子们的气味。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;When the two meerkats had wound their way out of the tight embrace, the sister lowered her head and showed her mother the wondrous thing they had discovered. The light now seemed abuzz, covering the sister’s head in feathery jumps. The little meerkat looked up at its mother and asked, “Can we bring it out mum?”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;两只狐獴挣脱了妈妈紧紧的拥抱，狐獴姐姐低下头，让妈妈看看他俩发现的这团奇妙美好的小东西。那只发光的小东西有点吵，在狐獴姐姐毛茸茸的头顶上跳跃着。小狐獴抬头望向妈妈，又问：“妈妈，我们可以送它出去吗？”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Viktoria Borodinova from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/24-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 