<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quarantine Chronicles</title>
    <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Quarantine Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 18:45:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/johannabernatzky.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第十一天：风不会停，但风向会变</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-3/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-3/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-3/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a far-away country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;埃尔姆山麓克尼格斯卢特尔（Königslutter am Elm）天气特别好，阳光灿烂得让人倍感精神。今日的太阳和舒适宜人的天气让我想起了地中海岛国—塞浦路斯。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The weather in Königslutter am Elm is wonderful, the splendid sun puts all feelings into stark relief. The sunshine and the pleasant weather remind me of an island nation in the Mediterranean – Cyprus.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;听着窗外的鸟儿欢声歌唱，很难不被它们的愉悦所感染。小贝前院的果树随风起舞，透过落地玻璃映在客厅墙面的树影也跟着舞动。叶影弯弯，中间隔着白色的阳光，随风而动，好似流水的波纹。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The joy of the birds chirping away outside the window is contagious. The tree in Johanna’s front yard dances in the wind, making the shadow it throws through the floor-length windows dance along on the living room wall. The shadow leaves float on white spaces, their movement in the wind making ripples in the water.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我盯着这流动的美丽影子看得有些入神，想起半个多月前，在塞浦路斯和Airbnb房东Alex在山中一个宁静的水库钓鱼。山上的植被早已披上春天的新衣，山间小路上有许多小花盛开，白的紫的，粉的蓝的，还有带尖刺灌木上开着的鲜艳小黄花。记得沿路穿过花丛时，被黄色山花枝干上的小刺扎到，还有扎进衣物的刺儿。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The sight of the flowing shadows is entrancing, it takes me back a fortnight to Cyprus, where my Airbnb host Alex took me fishing to a quiet reservoir. The trees and bushes on the mountains had already put on their new spring clothes. Flowers bloomed all around the mountain paths, white and purple, pink and blue, yellow on bristly branches. I remember the thorns on branches budding in yellow brushing past me as I walked through the flowers, some piercing my clothes.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;当然，那天记忆最深刻的还是风和水纹。不到五点出发，在水库附近见到一大早霸个好位置的垂钓者，还看到了山里的日出。那天是阳光明媚的日子，但山中清冷的风足以让坐在一旁的我打个冷颤。我一直祈祷风快点停，Alex却和我说风是不会停的，只会改变方向，我只好改口祈祷风不要往我们这边吹。我一边吃着三明治，一边观察水面的纹路。水波时而朝着西南流动，时而变向，被风推向岸的另一端。那里的水很清澈，可以见到水底泥土映有波纹影子，像是有人在泥上画了许多条波浪线。对我来说，风只要是吹到我脸上的，风向似乎都是一样的。但是水波的影子用它的方式悄悄告知我风的动向。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Of course, what I remember most clearly from that day is the wind, and the ripples in the water. We set out before 5. At the reservoir, we found others already who had used the early morning to scout out a good spot for fishing. We watched the sun rise over the mountains. That day, the sun was blazing, but the cold breeze cooled me to a shiver. I prayed for the wind to stop. Alex told me the wind will never stop, but it may change direction, so I started praying for it not to blow towards us. I sat eating a sandwich, watching the water ripple. The waves changed direction from time to time, pushed around by the wind towards this or that shore. In the clear water, I could see ripples in the sand as well, as if someone had drawn the waves into the mud. It was hard for me to tell where the wind was blowing from, but the dancing shadows of the waves quietly betrayed its direction.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;偶尔回想起，会觉得“风不会停，但风向会改变”的说法充满智慧，很具深意。虽然现在还不知道为什么我会有这样的想法，但是不急，可能很久以后回看自己的生活，将点串联起来，说不准能真的看到里面的智慧。看到像流水波纹影子的树影会想起那日和Alex钓鱼的场景：塞浦路斯的太阳、山花、接连上钩的小鱼、把小鱼吃掉却死活不上钩的大鱼、水库的宁静、坐在岸旁偶尔睡着的自己以及好吃的三明治。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;When I think back to this day, “the wind will not stop, but it may change direction” seems to ring full of wisdom. I am not sure what exactly it means yet, but I am in no hurry. Maybe when I look back on my life, at moments like pearls on a string, it will fall into place. As I look over the shadowy leaves floating around, I think back to the day I spent fishing with Alex: the Cypriot sun, the mountain flowers, the tiny fish caught on the hook, the big fish that swallow the tiny fish whole without ever getting stuck on the hook, the quiet of the reservoir, and me, sitting overlooking the water, dozing off occasionally and enjoying a sandwich.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Sophie.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-3/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 11: Heat</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-april/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-april/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-april/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a far-away country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The heat was stifling. Molly had seen it from the window as the plane descended, the way the air flickered over the runway like it was desperately waiting for a breeze to take it away. She could feel it creeping up through the soles of her shoes and dripping down the back of her neck. It was an all-commanding heat, eradicating all thought and emotion not directly related to it. It was probably better this way.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;天气热得令人窒息。茉莉趁着飞机降落时，盯着窗外的景色，空气闷热得到静止，似乎急需一阵清风。然而，气流微动，或许会有风的到来。茉莉可以感觉到闷热的气息滴落在她的后颈，蔓延到她的脚底。随着一股难以忍受的炙热而来的是许多想法和情绪。这样也不坏。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Without the heat, the tears that had started to tickle at her eyes as the acceleration had punched her into her seat might have finally squeezed their way out. She had distracted them with predictable romantic comedies, hadn’t allowed her own thoughts to gain land. Now she felt the heat suck her tear ducts dry, leaving nothing but a heaviness under the eyes and a deep exhaustion.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;泪水在眼眶里打滚得直叫茉莉眼睛发痒，要不是气温炎热，眼泪早就掉下来了。茉莉努力想着在飞机上看过的爱情喜剧，不然她就要哭出来。现在她觉得炎热的空气将她的泪水烘干了，眼下只留有一丝沉重与疲惫。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The way to the carpark seemed endless, her parents chattering away with their driver in a language they hadn’t thought necessary to impart on their daughter. Their excitement had been so contagious back home. A year in the sun, in the country the two of them had studied from afar for so long. This was a great honour, they had said, it was rare that this secretive land extended invitations to scholars.  Molly had been swept up in the preparations, there hadn’t been a minute for doubts, it hadn’t started sinking in until the border officer had handed her back her passport – DEPARTED. For a whole year she would be departed, the only bridge to her friends a blurry webcam picture.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;茉莉走去停车场的路似乎没有尽头，她的父母和司机交谈着，自觉不会影响到女儿的心情。茉莉父母在家的时候就很激动了，这样的情绪很具感染力。阳光下的一年，他们做了很久有关这个国家的研究。父母说这真的是极大的荣幸，这片神秘的土地很少向学者发出邀请。茉莉的父母毫不犹豫地接受邀请，茉莉几乎得马上跟着一起做准备，直到她从边境人员那里拿回护照，盖上出境印章，她才真正相信自己要离开了。茉莉将远离家乡一年，只能通过模糊的视讯联络家乡的朋友。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slam! The closing taxi door shook Molly from her daze, the heat slowly retreating as the A/C whirred into life. She rested her forehead against the window and let the oranges and greens outside fly past. She felt her tiredness dragging her down. But there was something outside that kept her afloat just above unconsciousness. Her eyes were fixed on a glittering bird, feathers in pink, green, blue, yellow, keeping pace with their car. It had come to greet her, she was sure. Its gaze made something flutter in Molly’s chest, something she couldn’t quite place as she drifted on the edge of sleep, something quietly wonderful.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;计程车门砰一声关上！关门声把茉莉拖回现实之中，车中的冷气驱逐了闷热的气息。茉莉把额头靠向车窗，看着窗外的橘色绿色划过。倦意拖着她下沉。但是车窗外有吸引到她的东西。茉莉目不转睛地看向一只闪亮的小鸟，它有粉色、绿色、蓝色和黄色的羽毛，和他们的车子保持同样的速度。小鸟飞来和她打招呼，茉莉非常确定。小鸟的注视让茉莉心跳变快，这是美好的，让快要睡着的她保持清醒的小鸟。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by spoba from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-april/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第十天：一人的世界</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-2/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-2/ -&lt;p&gt;You wake up in an empty world. What happens?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我在空无一人的大街上漫无目的地行走，打量着昨天还是人潮涌动的街道。不知道发生了什么事，一觉睡醒之后，世界就成了这个样子了。我已经独占了地球三个小时了，对现状还是挺满意的，十分肯定我今天不用上班。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I amble along the empty avenue, no destination in mind. I observe a street that resounded with the sound of scuffling feet just yesterday. I don’t know what happened, when I woke up this morning, I found the world in this state. I have been alone in the world for three hours. So far I am quite happy, one thing I know for sure is that I don’t have to go to work today.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;好久没有好好看过广州的东山口了，从小到大，我都很喜欢这里中西结合的洋房别墅，红砖墙面，白色栏柱，赭色门窗，映衬着周围深绿色的大榕树。今天只有我在这里，没有其他学生和游客。周围的小吃店都还开着，虽然没有人，但是食物还是供应着的。实在是太棒了！我跟随着香味，走进一家牛杂店，牛杂萝卜还是滚烫的，我自己拿着碗盛了熬煮入味的牛杂和焖得软糯的萝卜，再撒上蒜蓉辣椒酱，坐在树荫下，享用我最喜欢的小吃。啊，实在是人间美味！同时也在想，下一样该吃什么？&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I haven’t looked around this district of Guangzhou in a long time. I’ve always liked the mansions and villas, the clash of West and East in the red brick walls, the white fences, doors and windows framed in auburn, all safely shaded beneath the verdant banyan trees. Today I am the only one here, there are no students, no tourists. The little eateries all around have kept their doors open, and although they are empty of people, they are still full of food. Perfect! I follow my nose into a shop that promises boiling hot servings of beef tripe with radish. I help myself to a heaping bowl full of soft juicy tripe braised with soft sticky radish. I top it off with garlic and chilli paste and find a tree to shade this treat, my favourite snack. Ah, this taste, heaven on earth! As I eat, I start planning what to try next.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;不知道这样的世界能让我独占多久，但接下来我肯定会抓紧时间尽量多吃！&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I don’t know how long I will be left here all alone, but I am resolved to use the time I have to savour all I can!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Irina Iriser from Pexels.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-2/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 10: Imagine</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/2-april/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/2-april/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/2-april/ -&lt;p&gt;You wake up in an empty world. What happens?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;There is nothing here. Or is there? Maybe there will be. I will turn on the light and make my own creation. I will make colours first. Pulsing red, sparkling purple, waving green. When everything is colours, they will start dancing and swirling, flowing into a great vortex. Then I will make sound. A dark vibrato that pulls and pushes at my colours. Splendid chords will bring order into the chaos, major yellows, minor blues. Colour and sound is all I contribute, the rest will make itself.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;这里什么都没有。我甚至在想“这里”存在吗？也许未来会存在。那样的话，我会打开灯，进行创作。先选色彩，热情的红、闪耀的紫和明快的绿。一切都有着色，它们开始舞动旋转，流转成巨型漩涡。我再为这个世界增添点声响，颤音深沉，随着我选用的颜色抖动。壮美的和声颠覆秩序，引入混乱，大笔的黄，少量的蓝。色彩与声音是我带来的全部礼物，其余皆是它们的造化。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The greens and browns will grow each other into forests, filled with rustles and chirps. The blues will separate into thundering waves and ringing heavens. With great crashes, greys will build up cliffs and gorges, red rumbling far below. Once it is all done, I will invite. Eyes to glisten in the light, ears to hear. Voices to join in the symphony and make their own chords. I will sit back and listen to it all, watch the colours blossom and fade in perpetuity. This is my gift.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;绿与棕融为一片森林，里面树叶的沙沙作响，鸟虫的吱吱喳喳。蓝色生出如雷般嘈杂的海浪和敲响钟声的天堂。灰色剧烈撞击，造就峭壁峡谷，红色在底下低吟。我完成这份作品便会发出邀请。光明之处，眼睛泛着光，耳朵聆听着，所有的声音都融入到交响乐中，成为配合的和声。我会坐在一旁，欣赏所有乐章，观赏在绽放后逐渐退场的色彩。这是我送来的礼物。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by 8926 from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/2-april/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第九天：庆祝</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-1/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-1/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;席卷欧洲的丧尸病毒终于被清除完毕了，新闻宣布解除宵禁令，生活也重回正轨。凯丽没有经历过战争，没有感受过冷战的恐惧，却经历了如同战时的丧尸病毒封城居家禁令。不过，既然生活重归平静，那她也开始计划要如何与朋友们一同庆祝。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Europe has finally rid itself of the zombie virus, newspapers report the lifting of all restrictions, life returns to normal. Kelly, not having lived through any wars, having grown up without a trace of the Cold War’s existential dread, now knows what it is like to live under lockdown in a city besieged. But now that normality has reinstated itself, she begins to plan a celebration with her friends.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;眼下凯丽还有生长得很好的绿叶蔬菜，或许她可以办一个绿色蔬菜派对，邀请朋友们一起吃菜。但只有沙拉吃也未免有些无聊，她还需要想一些新点子，把这些蔬菜利用起来。这些蔬菜也是她这几个月独居生活的见证了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Some of her beautifully grown green vegetables remain, maybe she will invite her friends to a vegetable feast. Then again, a salad-only feast seems a little boring. She will have to think of some other dishes to show off her greens. After all, they have documented her solitary life over the past months so well.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;在凯丽搜索创意菜谱时，娜塔莉打电话邀请她参加葡萄丰收酿酒派对，品尝他们家今年收获的葡萄，还有先前闭门保命期间酿的的果酒。危险一过，大家都沉浸在对未来生活的期许中，都想好好庆祝被迫分隔开的特殊时期的终结。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As she looks for recipes, Kelly receives a call from Natalie, who invites her to a party of grape harvesting and wine making. There will be freshly picked grapes to taste, and the wine the family has been maturing during the lockdown. With the danger defeated, dreams for the future start to sprout again, people no longer forced into separation now long for celebration.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;独居躲避丧尸病毒时，凯丽头一回体验对未来的恐惧、不安与不知生活何时恢复正常的绝望，才发觉原本生活的世界是如此便利和连通。一个人独处的时候，她想了很多，现在凯丽只想和亲朋好友们好好庆祝充满希望的正常生活，开启新的篇章。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Locked away in fear of the zombie virus, Kelly feared for her future for the first time in her life. The anxiety, not knowing when life would fall back into place put it all into perspective. She now understands how comfortable, how connected her life used to be. She had a lot of time to think, left all by herself.  Now all she wants to do is celebrate the hopeful ordinariness of life, she wants to turn over the page.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Pexels from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/4-yue-1/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 9: Full Moon at Orchard House</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Leon lived on the tenth floor of Orchard House. Whoever had chosen this name must have possessed an obscene dose of optimism, Orchard House was about as far from green as you could get. Layers of concrete squashed over each other, the building imposed its presence on the neighbourhood like a prison guard. Try as you might, wherever you went one of its windows was watching you.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;里昂住在果园楼的十楼。不知取名人何者，但一定是极其乐观的人。只要你看看果园楼，就知道这里和绿色毫不沾边。取而代之的是一层又一层的混凝土，显得这座楼像是邻近地区的看守狱卒一样。你大可一试，无论走到哪里，总会感觉到某个窗子里传来的注视。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Most days, Leon didn’t look forward much to going home. School was bright and exciting, full of new things to be learned, while home was tinged with grey and burdened with worries that seeped out of the walls on rainy days. But once every month, when the moon was at its brightest, Orchard House transformed. While to a passer-by it wouldn’t seem any different, anyone inside the building when the last slice of sun disappeared behind the horizon witnessed the change.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;绝大多数日子里，里昂并不期待回家。学校是那么明亮，活力四射，充满全新的知识。他的家则是灰暗的，每逢雨天，他总是要担心墙会渗出水来。每逢满月那天，月色皎洁明亮，果园楼总会发生奇幻的变化。过路人瞧去并无不同，但楼内居民却能在最后一丝夕照退却到地平线后，发现果园楼的变化。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It started with a tremor. Picture frames trembling on the walls, chairs jumping around. Then a crackling silence, and finally the sharp ring of a bell. Leon jumped up from his bed and ran into the living room, where he found his sister Clara already waiting, carrying a plate of biscuits. Their mum was standing by the door, beckoning excitedly. Through the crack at the bottom of the door, Leon saw a shimmering light.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;首先，果园楼会有一丝颤动。墙上的画框会摇晃，楼中的椅子会晃动。随之而来的是沉默，最终是钟声敲响。里昂跳下床，跑进客厅，见到妹妹克拉拉也在等待，带着一盘饼干。妈妈倚靠房门，心情激动。里昂看见从门边缝隙流入家中的闪亮月光。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Today he was the one to open the door. He knew that tonight, it would not lead to the naked corridor with its clinically white neon lights. Tonight the door opened on a celebration. A meadow stretched out in front of Leon and his family, soft green grass tickled their feet as they stepped onto it. And there, he could see doors all around the meadow opening. Some people came alone, some in twos and threes. All carried food and smiles to be shared. From somewhere Leon could hear music, maybe one of their neighbours had left their radio on.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今晚是由里昂开门。他知道今晚门后不再是空荡荡的映着白月光的长廊，取而代之的是一场庆典。开门之后，里昂和他的家人来到一片草坪上，他们光脚踏上草坪，柔软的小草挠的他们的脚板有点痒。这里还有独自前来的人，有三五成群的人。所有人分享着食物和笑容。里昂听见不知何处传来的音乐，可能是邻居忘记关收音机了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The full moon shone quietly over Orchard House, illuminating the festive meadow. It watched over the celebration of life, of another month of discoveries, losses, heartbreaks, successes, ready to be shared with a friendly ear eager to listen. Tonight, neighbours became friends under the soft glow, and even though they knew that the night could not last forever, in this moment they were happy.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;圆月的光芒静静地洒落在果园楼，照亮了喜庆的草坪，看着人们庆祝着生命、新的发现、损失、心碎、成功，做好了聆听故事的准备。今晚，住客们在柔光下作伴，他们虽知满月的光芒不会永远持续，但此时此刻他们是快乐的。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Free-Photos from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第八天：海边散步</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a poem full of social distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我在海边散步，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I walk on the beach&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;享受着地中海的阳光沙滩，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bask in the Mediterranean sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;喝着鲜榨橙子，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fresh orange juice in hand&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;和人群保持着距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I keep my distance from the people&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我感到很安全。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;And feel safe.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一声问好，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A greeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;有人跟来搭讪。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A stranger strikes up a conversation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;恰好我一个人也无聊，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bored with myself&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;回了他几句。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I exchange a few words with him.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;但陌生人没有保持社交距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;But the stranger approaches past social distancing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;企图调情，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For a flirt.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让我烦躁和惊恐。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I am anxious and scared.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;疫情期间，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In this pandemic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;没有两米社交距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two-metre closeness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;没有口罩，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unmasked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让我惧怕。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scares me.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Sophie.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 8: Alone at Lidl</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a poem full of social distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I wonder why&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我想知道&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;We don’t look at each other anymore&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;大家为何不再看彼此一眼&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pushing our shopping carts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;推挤着购物车&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;past      each      other&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;经 过 彼此&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;We stare resolutely ahead&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我们盯着远处&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Or find a particularly eye-catching&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;或是发现了特别抢眼的&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bunch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;of&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;束&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bananas     to investigate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;香蕉用来观察&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maybe we are scared&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;也许我们都害怕&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;That this small human interaction might be enough&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;人与人之间小小的互动就足以&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To contaminate uswithcloseness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让对方染病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Twometresdisappearoverthemeetingofeyes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一旦对视两米的社交距离就会凭空消失&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Or maybe we cannot bear it&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;或许我们无法忍受&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It hurts too much to see and not touch, not hug, not hold&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;见到彼此，却无法碰触，拥抱，握手&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Today I am resolved to look.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今天，我决定去看。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Steve Buissinne on Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第七天：我在天堂过得很好</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a story about a ghost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一个角落，天堂（GPS无法定位）&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A corner of heaven (No GPS signal)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“我是在哪里？”刚刚睡醒的乔揉了揉自己的眼睛，头有点疼，昨晚又喝了太多酒。他睁开疲倦的双眼，环顾四周，发现自己在全然陌生的地方，大概是还没睡醒吧，他决定合上眼睛，再睡一会儿。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Where am I?” Joe has just woken up. He rubs the sleep from his eyes. His head hurts from the drinks the night before. He opens his tired eyes and looks around him to discover he finds himself in a strange place. He must be dreaming still, so he decides to close his eyes and sleep a while longer.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;不知道又过了多久，乔总算是醒了，倦意全无，然而他发现周围的环境依旧很陌生，不是他在莱科沃斯（Lake Worth）的公寓。他究竟是在哪儿？这里很光亮，一切都很干净，也很安静。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After a long while, Joe finally wakes again, this time completely refreshed. His surroundings however are unchanged in their foreignness, this is not his apartment in Lake Worth. Where on earth is he? It is bright here, everything is clean and quiet.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔努力坐起身来，惊讶地发现他好像睡在了云上，突然他感到害怕，他不会摔下去吧？到底发生了什么？为什么他一觉醒来会在这个奇怪的地方？这里没有电脑，没有手机，没有互联网，人影也不见一个。乔用力掐了掐自己的胳膊，还挺疼的，说明他是清醒的。他已经有一年多没磕过药了，不可能会有幻觉的。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe struggles into a sitting position only to make the startling discovery that he seems to have fallen asleep on a cloud. Suddenly he is scared, what if he falls? What is going on? Why has he woken up in this strange place? He doesn’t have his computer, nor his phone, there is no internet. He is completely alone, there are no other humans to be seen. Joe pinches his arm, it hurts. He must be awake. He has been clean for a year, this is not a trip.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;不知又过了多久，有在云上行走的路人见到他，“Howdy, bud!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After another long while, someone approaches him on the clouds. “Howdy, bud!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔惊喜地回了一句，“你好呀！你知道我们在哪吗？&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe, surprised, only replies “Hey! Do you know where we are?”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;路人见怪不怪的样子，“恭喜你上天堂了！”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The passerby seems unfazed. “Congrats for making it to heaven!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔一脸困惑地问：“天堂？”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe is utterly bewildered. “Heaven?”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;路人拍了拍乔的肩膀，“对呀，我们都死了。看开点吧，至少我们没下地狱嘛。”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The stranger pats him on the shoulder. “That’s right, we’re all dead here. Chin up buddy, at least we’re not in hell.”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;又过了大半年，乔慢慢适应了天堂的新生活，挺不错的，过去几年的积攒的脂肪也消耗掉了，恢复到了他曾经引以为傲的健康身材。他偶尔会悄悄看看地上的亲友，默默祝福他们。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Months pass by before Joe starts to get used to his new life in heaven. It’s not bad actually, he’s managed to burn off all the fat built up over the years and is back to the healthy body he used to be so proud of. Sometimes he secretly visits his friends and family and quietly watches over them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;有一天，乔感觉到地上的朋友们在想他，原来今天是他的26岁生日。他想知道想念他的朋友们都在干什么，决定随机看看一个朋友。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;One day, Joe realises that many friends on earth are thinking about him. It is his 26th birthday. He would like to know what they are doing, these friends who miss him. So he picks a train of thought to ride to one of them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;纽卡斯尔，英国&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Newcastle, England&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;苏菲在浏览脸书，犹豫要不要在乔的时间线上留言，祝他生日快乐，毕竟他都不在了，也看不到了。苏菲想起曾经寄过生日卡到美国去给乔，便有点伤感，乔还那么年轻，他的生活才刚刚步入正轨，有新的转机。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sophie is browsing Facebook. Should she leave a message on Joe’s wall, wish him a happy birthday? He’s not there anymore, he won’t see it. Sophie remembers the birthday cards she sent to Joe in America. It makes her sad. Joe was so young, he had just straightened his life out when it decided to throw him for a loop.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;算了，还是不留言了。苏菲合上电脑，双手托着下巴，发着呆，她原本计划明年暑假去美国旅游的，还可以和乔见个面，大家都做了8年的笔友了。唯一一次大家在同一片大陆的时候还是四年半前，但最后因为苏菲要高考，乔在上海一年的交换学习要结束了，大家没有成功会面。那时候，都觉得还年轻，以后还是有很多机会的。万万没想到……&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No, she won’t write anything. Sophie closes her laptop, rests her chin in her hands and lets her mind wander. Next year over the summer, she was going to travel to America, was going to see Joe, her pen pal of 8 years. Four and a half years have passed since they last were on the same continent at the same time. But with Sophie busy preparing for final exams and Joe’s year abroad in Shanghai passing by so quickly, they had missed each other. Back then Sophie was sure they would meet each other someday, they were young after all. How could she have known?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;明天还要上学，她还是早点睡吧。希望乔在另一个世界里会过得很棒啦。那天晚上，苏菲做了一个梦，梦见了红发的乔，他还是和以前一样瘦，乔还和她说，“Don’t worry, I am doing very well in another world.” 苏菲感到欣慰，拥抱了乔，拍了拍他的背，说“I am so glad to know that.” 梦里他们还聊了好久的天，只是苏菲睡醒之后都不记得他们说过什么了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sophie has classes in the morning, so she goes to bed early. She hopes that Joe is happy in another world. That evening, Sophie has a dream. In her dream she sees Joe, with his ginger hair and slim stature. Joe says to her “Don’t worry, I am doing very well in another world.” Sophie is filled with relief, she gives Joe a hug and pats his back. “I am so glad to know that.” They talk for a long time in her dream, but when Sophie wakes up, she doesn’t remember a word.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by skeeze from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 7: Lady of the Castle</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a story about a ghost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I was born during a dreadful winter storm in the servants’ quarters at a great castle. I never met the lords and ladies who belonged upstairs in the satin-stuffed rooms. My mother deemed me too young, too loud, too filthy and so the kitchen was where I spent most of my time. One of the stern-faced men whose portraits now stared us down from in between marble columns had cherished solitude and quiet so much that he had banished the busy kitchen from the castle keep entirely. It had been moved to a cavernous hall underneath a guard tower which was rumoured to have imprisoned in its upper floors many who had disturbed the peace of the lord, amongst them a persistent debt collector sent all the way from London. Stories of these unfortunate souls locked away behind cold stone walls took hold in my head. Tucked into the corner by the firewood, I liked to imagine myself one of them, haunting the castle long after my time. Maybe that is why I stayed behind.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我在一座伟大城堡的佣人居室里出生，当时寒风凛冽。我生前从未见过住在楼上华丽起居室中的贵族家庭。我的母亲嫌我弱小吵闹，太过肮脏，所以我绝大部分的时间都是在厨房度过的。有一位板着脸的领主喜欢独处和宁静，以至于他把忙碌的厨房迁出了主堡。他的画像现在悬挂在大理石柱之间，居高临下地打量着我们。厨房搬到了护卫塔楼底下如同洞穴的厅堂，据说此处曾经关押了许多扰了领主清静的人，有的还是从伦敦远道而来不依不饶的讨债人。我总是记着这些被关押的不幸的灵魂。我蜷缩在壁炉旁的小角落，想象自己也是被关押的人，化作厉鬼在城堡里游荡。或许，这也是我仍留在城堡的原因吧。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I died on a summer day, slipped on the servants’ stairs and there I stood, looking down at myself. It was a shame about the lovely pinafore my mother had sewn for me, now dotted in red. The first decades were torture. I watched my family wither away, saw buildings fall into ruin. I was helpless, all I could do was witness. Then, slowly, a sense of freedom started to seep in. I was now the oldest being in the castle, I had had time enough to explore its dungeons, its hidden staircases, its drafty corridors, its sun-filled sitting rooms. I saw ages pass by, children born, tapestries put up and torn down, lords and ladies circling around in a never-ending dance. I roam the castle still. The kitchen has long since fallen into disrepair, idle travellers now amble down the stairs which once resounded with the frantic feet of maids. I still like to visit the scene of my death from time to time. Open your eyes and see.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;某个夏日里，我在佣人的楼梯滑倒，意外摔死了。我的灵魂出窍，俯视着自己死去的躯壳。母亲为我缝制的洋裙上点满了鲜血，可惜了一条漂亮的裙子。我死后的几十年挺受折磨的，目睹家人的死亡和城堡建筑的衰败。我只能做旁观者，对于发生的一切都无能为力。后来，一种自由的感觉渐渐传来。我现在可是城堡里最古老的存在了，时间充裕，可以自由探索城堡的地牢，隐藏的楼梯密道，冷风穿堂的走廊，以及充满阳光的起居室。我目睹岁月流逝，孩童出生，墙上挂毯的更换，贵族男女无尽的旋转舞步。我依然会在城堡里游荡。曾经玩耍过的厨房早已破败，昔日楼梯间回荡着女仆们匆忙急促的脚步声，而如今充斥着闲来没事的游客。我偶尔还会去我死去的地方看看。睁大你的眼睛，看仔细了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by similitude on Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 