<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quarantine Chronicles</title>
    <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Quarantine Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/johannabernatzky.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第八天：海边散步</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a poem full of social distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我在海边散步，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I walk on the beach&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;享受着地中海的阳光沙滩，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bask in the Mediterranean sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;喝着鲜榨橙子，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fresh orange juice in hand&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;和人群保持着距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I keep my distance from the people&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我感到很安全。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;And feel safe.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一声问好，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A greeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;有人跟来搭讪。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A stranger strikes up a conversation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;恰好我一个人也无聊，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bored with myself&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;回了他几句。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I exchange a few words with him.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;但陌生人没有保持社交距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;But the stranger approaches past social distancing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;企图调情，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For a flirt.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让我烦躁和惊恐。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I am anxious and scared.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;疫情期间，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In this pandemic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;没有两米社交距离，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two-metre closeness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;没有口罩，&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unmasked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让我惧怕。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scares me.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Sophie.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-31/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 8: Alone at Lidl</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a poem full of social distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I wonder why&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我想知道&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;We don’t look at each other anymore&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;大家为何不再看彼此一眼&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pushing our shopping carts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;推挤着购物车&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;past      each      other&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;经 过 彼此&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;We stare resolutely ahead&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我们盯着远处&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Or find a particularly eye-catching&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;或是发现了特别抢眼的&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bunch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;of&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;束&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bananas     to investigate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;香蕉用来观察&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maybe we are scared&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;也许我们都害怕&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;That this small human interaction might be enough&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;人与人之间小小的互动就足以&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To contaminate uswithcloseness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;让对方染病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Twometresdisappearoverthemeetingofeyes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一旦对视两米的社交距离就会凭空消失&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Or maybe we cannot bear it&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;或许我们无法忍受&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It hurts too much to see and not touch, not hug, not hold&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;见到彼此，却无法碰触，拥抱，握手&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Today I am resolved to look.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今天，我决定去看。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Steve Buissinne on Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第七天：我在天堂过得很好</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a story about a ghost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一个角落，天堂（GPS无法定位）&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A corner of heaven (No GPS signal)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“我是在哪里？”刚刚睡醒的乔揉了揉自己的眼睛，头有点疼，昨晚又喝了太多酒。他睁开疲倦的双眼，环顾四周，发现自己在全然陌生的地方，大概是还没睡醒吧，他决定合上眼睛，再睡一会儿。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Where am I?” Joe has just woken up. He rubs the sleep from his eyes. His head hurts from the drinks the night before. He opens his tired eyes and looks around him to discover he finds himself in a strange place. He must be dreaming still, so he decides to close his eyes and sleep a while longer.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;不知道又过了多久，乔总算是醒了，倦意全无，然而他发现周围的环境依旧很陌生，不是他在莱科沃斯（Lake Worth）的公寓。他究竟是在哪儿？这里很光亮，一切都很干净，也很安静。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After a long while, Joe finally wakes again, this time completely refreshed. His surroundings however are unchanged in their foreignness, this is not his apartment in Lake Worth. Where on earth is he? It is bright here, everything is clean and quiet.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔努力坐起身来，惊讶地发现他好像睡在了云上，突然他感到害怕，他不会摔下去吧？到底发生了什么？为什么他一觉醒来会在这个奇怪的地方？这里没有电脑，没有手机，没有互联网，人影也不见一个。乔用力掐了掐自己的胳膊，还挺疼的，说明他是清醒的。他已经有一年多没磕过药了，不可能会有幻觉的。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe struggles into a sitting position only to make the startling discovery that he seems to have fallen asleep on a cloud. Suddenly he is scared, what if he falls? What is going on? Why has he woken up in this strange place? He doesn’t have his computer, nor his phone, there is no internet. He is completely alone, there are no other humans to be seen. Joe pinches his arm, it hurts. He must be awake. He has been clean for a year, this is not a trip.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;不知又过了多久，有在云上行走的路人见到他，“Howdy, bud!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After another long while, someone approaches him on the clouds. “Howdy, bud!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔惊喜地回了一句，“你好呀！你知道我们在哪吗？&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe, surprised, only replies “Hey! Do you know where we are?”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;路人见怪不怪的样子，“恭喜你上天堂了！”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The passerby seems unfazed. “Congrats for making it to heaven!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;乔一脸困惑地问：“天堂？”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joe is utterly bewildered. “Heaven?”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;路人拍了拍乔的肩膀，“对呀，我们都死了。看开点吧，至少我们没下地狱嘛。”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The stranger pats him on the shoulder. “That’s right, we’re all dead here. Chin up buddy, at least we’re not in hell.”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;又过了大半年，乔慢慢适应了天堂的新生活，挺不错的，过去几年的积攒的脂肪也消耗掉了，恢复到了他曾经引以为傲的健康身材。他偶尔会悄悄看看地上的亲友，默默祝福他们。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Months pass by before Joe starts to get used to his new life in heaven. It’s not bad actually, he’s managed to burn off all the fat built up over the years and is back to the healthy body he used to be so proud of. Sometimes he secretly visits his friends and family and quietly watches over them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;有一天，乔感觉到地上的朋友们在想他，原来今天是他的26岁生日。他想知道想念他的朋友们都在干什么，决定随机看看一个朋友。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;One day, Joe realises that many friends on earth are thinking about him. It is his 26th birthday. He would like to know what they are doing, these friends who miss him. So he picks a train of thought to ride to one of them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;纽卡斯尔，英国&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Newcastle, England&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;苏菲在浏览脸书，犹豫要不要在乔的时间线上留言，祝他生日快乐，毕竟他都不在了，也看不到了。苏菲想起曾经寄过生日卡到美国去给乔，便有点伤感，乔还那么年轻，他的生活才刚刚步入正轨，有新的转机。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sophie is browsing Facebook. Should she leave a message on Joe’s wall, wish him a happy birthday? He’s not there anymore, he won’t see it. Sophie remembers the birthday cards she sent to Joe in America. It makes her sad. Joe was so young, he had just straightened his life out when it decided to throw him for a loop.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;算了，还是不留言了。苏菲合上电脑，双手托着下巴，发着呆，她原本计划明年暑假去美国旅游的，还可以和乔见个面，大家都做了8年的笔友了。唯一一次大家在同一片大陆的时候还是四年半前，但最后因为苏菲要高考，乔在上海一年的交换学习要结束了，大家没有成功会面。那时候，都觉得还年轻，以后还是有很多机会的。万万没想到……&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No, she won’t write anything. Sophie closes her laptop, rests her chin in her hands and lets her mind wander. Next year over the summer, she was going to travel to America, was going to see Joe, her pen pal of 8 years. Four and a half years have passed since they last were on the same continent at the same time. But with Sophie busy preparing for final exams and Joe’s year abroad in Shanghai passing by so quickly, they had missed each other. Back then Sophie was sure they would meet each other someday, they were young after all. How could she have known?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;明天还要上学，她还是早点睡吧。希望乔在另一个世界里会过得很棒啦。那天晚上，苏菲做了一个梦，梦见了红发的乔，他还是和以前一样瘦，乔还和她说，“Don’t worry, I am doing very well in another world.” 苏菲感到欣慰，拥抱了乔，拍了拍他的背，说“I am so glad to know that.” 梦里他们还聊了好久的天，只是苏菲睡醒之后都不记得他们说过什么了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sophie has classes in the morning, so she goes to bed early. She hopes that Joe is happy in another world. That evening, Sophie has a dream. In her dream she sees Joe, with his ginger hair and slim stature. Joe says to her “Don’t worry, I am doing very well in another world.” Sophie is filled with relief, she gives Joe a hug and pats his back. “I am so glad to know that.” They talk for a long time in her dream, but when Sophie wakes up, she doesn’t remember a word.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by skeeze from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-30/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 7: Lady of the Castle</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write a story about a ghost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I was born during a dreadful winter storm in the servants’ quarters at a great castle. I never met the lords and ladies who belonged upstairs in the satin-stuffed rooms. My mother deemed me too young, too loud, too filthy and so the kitchen was where I spent most of my time. One of the stern-faced men whose portraits now stared us down from in between marble columns had cherished solitude and quiet so much that he had banished the busy kitchen from the castle keep entirely. It had been moved to a cavernous hall underneath a guard tower which was rumoured to have imprisoned in its upper floors many who had disturbed the peace of the lord, amongst them a persistent debt collector sent all the way from London. Stories of these unfortunate souls locked away behind cold stone walls took hold in my head. Tucked into the corner by the firewood, I liked to imagine myself one of them, haunting the castle long after my time. Maybe that is why I stayed behind.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我在一座伟大城堡的佣人居室里出生，当时寒风凛冽。我生前从未见过住在楼上华丽起居室中的贵族家庭。我的母亲嫌我弱小吵闹，太过肮脏，所以我绝大部分的时间都是在厨房度过的。有一位板着脸的领主喜欢独处和宁静，以至于他把忙碌的厨房迁出了主堡。他的画像现在悬挂在大理石柱之间，居高临下地打量着我们。厨房搬到了护卫塔楼底下如同洞穴的厅堂，据说此处曾经关押了许多扰了领主清静的人，有的还是从伦敦远道而来不依不饶的讨债人。我总是记着这些被关押的不幸的灵魂。我蜷缩在壁炉旁的小角落，想象自己也是被关押的人，化作厉鬼在城堡里游荡。或许，这也是我仍留在城堡的原因吧。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I died on a summer day, slipped on the servants’ stairs and there I stood, looking down at myself. It was a shame about the lovely pinafore my mother had sewn for me, now dotted in red. The first decades were torture. I watched my family wither away, saw buildings fall into ruin. I was helpless, all I could do was witness. Then, slowly, a sense of freedom started to seep in. I was now the oldest being in the castle, I had had time enough to explore its dungeons, its hidden staircases, its drafty corridors, its sun-filled sitting rooms. I saw ages pass by, children born, tapestries put up and torn down, lords and ladies circling around in a never-ending dance. I roam the castle still. The kitchen has long since fallen into disrepair, idle travellers now amble down the stairs which once resounded with the frantic feet of maids. I still like to visit the scene of my death from time to time. Open your eyes and see.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;某个夏日里，我在佣人的楼梯滑倒，意外摔死了。我的灵魂出窍，俯视着自己死去的躯壳。母亲为我缝制的洋裙上点满了鲜血，可惜了一条漂亮的裙子。我死后的几十年挺受折磨的，目睹家人的死亡和城堡建筑的衰败。我只能做旁观者，对于发生的一切都无能为力。后来，一种自由的感觉渐渐传来。我现在可是城堡里最古老的存在了，时间充裕，可以自由探索城堡的地牢，隐藏的楼梯密道，冷风穿堂的走廊，以及充满阳光的起居室。我目睹岁月流逝，孩童出生，墙上挂毯的更换，贵族男女无尽的旋转舞步。我依然会在城堡里游荡。曾经玩耍过的厨房早已破败，昔日楼梯间回荡着女仆们匆忙急促的脚步声，而如今充斥着闲来没事的游客。我偶尔还会去我死去的地方看看。睁大你的眼睛，看仔细了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by similitude on Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第六天：一幅画，两棵树</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a painting you find online or on your walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;床头的画中有两颗生长在一起的大树，颜色一深一浅，枝干不多，绿意盎然。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In the painting at the foot of bed there are two trees twisted into each other. One is light, one is dark. Their branches are few in number but rich in green.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;看见树，想到尼采的《查拉图斯特拉如是说》，他写道：“其实人跟树是一样的，越是向往高处的阳光，它的根就越要伸向黑暗的地底”。随着年龄的增长，愈发觉得人总要直视自己的黑暗面，才能让光明的那面更好地生长，也明白单纯不和善良挂钩，人可以有过痛苦的经历，见过世间的残酷，依旧保有纯粹美好的一面，做出充满善意的选择。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The trees remind me of this quote from Nietzsche’s “Thus Spoke Zarathustra”: “But it is the same with man as with the tree. The more he seeks to rise into the height and light, the more vigorously do his roots struggle earthward, downward, into the dark, the deep.” The older I grow, the more I discover that to help your brightness develop, you must first look at your darkness. I understand that good isn’t always simple. People with painful experiences who have witnessed the world’s cruelty still have a purely beautiful side. They can still make the right choice.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;人真的很像树，可以立于土地之上，双脚如同树根，感受着大地给予的能量，体验着宇宙和世界的养分。像树一样扎根地上，让人感到很安心呀。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;People are really a lot like trees. When we stand on the ground, our feet become roots connected to the earth’s energy. We are nourished by the energy of the universe, of our planet. Planting our roots into the ground sets the mind at ease.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Painting by Klaus Rathgen.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 6: Nu Dans un Intérieur</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a painting you find online or on your walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This morning I woke up feeling fluffy inside and out. The soft pillow against my cheek, the aftereffects of a generous helping of vino. My nose was the first thing to spring into action. The faint smell of coffee drifting in from somewhere carried promise. I sat up in bed, slowly to not upset the cotton filling my head.  I carefully made my way over to the blinds, took a deep breath and threw them wide open. Light flooded the orange walls, danced over the painted flowers. Taking in the jubilantly blue sky, the clouds around my temples seemed to begin to clear.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今早起床，我感觉整个人都轻飘飘。我的脸靠在柔软的枕头上，这是葡萄酒喝多了的结果。我的鼻子最早苏醒，闻到了咖啡的淡香味。我坐在床上，缓慢起身，不想太过头晕，我小心地越过床前的屏风，深吸一口气，果断把屏风拉开。光线照射到橘色的墙壁上，映照着墙上的花。窗外的蓝天令人心旷神怡，太阳穴旁的白云似乎在散去。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I turned the shower to scalding heat and simply stood there, feeling my body finally shake off the last bits of fuzziness. I didn’t bother putting on a gown. Outside the window I could see nothing but blue, and the anonymity of a tourist shrouded me. I fixed my hair, brushed my teeth, secure in the knowledge that even if someone caught a glimpse of me, they would have no way of connecting this body to a real person. I would just be that to them, a nude study, a still image, a flash of skin.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我调好水温，淋着滚烫的洗澡水，感受着身体最后一丝疲倦的褪去。我懒得穿上浴袍。我只见窗外的蓝，我的游客身份保护了我。我整理完头发，刷完牙，确认即便有人看见我，他们也无法联想到我是谁。他们只会把我当作一具裸体，一幅静物画，一副皮囊。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I laid out my clothes on the bed, shields for my trip to the source of the still-wafting smell. The blue dress it would have to be, the sky called for it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我把衣物置于床上，准备换好衣服去喝咖啡。我一定会穿上蓝裙子，好搭配今日的蓝天。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Painting by Pierre Bonnard.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第五天：小鹿的樱花梦</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/ -&lt;p&gt;Go outside. Put on your writer hat. Try to notice 5 things to write about!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;小鹿和家人在田野里悠转，享受温暖和煦的阳光，吃着田间植被与落叶。明天要转夏令时了，小鹿兴奋地期待着，春天来了，天气应该会更舒服吧。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The little deer treaded lightly on the field, basking in the warm sunlight, grazing on plants and fallen leaves. It was the day before summer time and the little deer was excited. Spring was coming and with it the warmer temperatures it liked.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;最近的气温足够暖和，迎来了初春的花期，花树开始初吐芬芳，其中包括小鹿最喜欢的樱花树了。田野附近的樱花树已是娇艳盛开，每一朵小巧的樱花都微不足道，但仔细观看，层层重瓣繁复华丽。满树樱花蔚为观止，小鹿忍不住想象再过些时日，如若起风，樱花随风飘舞，如同落雪的美丽。啊，到时它可以在堆在地上的柔软落花里打滚，沾染樱花浅淡的馨香，亦或是把自己埋在花堆里，把陨落质柔的花瓣当作棉被，抵挡初春的清寒，它还可以尝尝樱花滋味，毕竟平时吃的都是绿色植被，难得有粉色的食材可用……&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The mild air had already blown in the first flowers of early spring. Plants were sprouting their first buds, amongst them the little deer’s favourite, the cherry trees. Next to the field stood a cherry in full bloom already. Its tiny delicate blossoms looked insignificant from a distance, but close up they revealed a luxurious abundance of petals, layer upon layer. The little deer stood admiring the tree. It imagined that in a few weeks, when the wind started blowing, it would take the petals with it and cover the ground in cherry snow. Oh, how nice it would be to roll around in the piled-up petals, to imprint their scent onto its fur. Or to bury itself under the soft cover of fallen blossoms and hide from the cold spells of early spring. And then to savour the petals’ taste would add a welcome dash of pink to its ever-green diet.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“看，那里有鹿！”小鹿闻声，抬头望向把它从樱花梦中吵醒的人，噢，原来是骑车的小贝。小贝又补充道，“看到了那几只吗？就在田里面。”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Look, there’s deer over there!” heard the deer suddenly. It raised its head to make out the one who had disturbed its cherry dreams. Ah, it was Johanna on a bicycle. “Did you see them? In the field!”, she added.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“看到了！”骑车跟在小贝身后的筱然回答。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“I did!”, said Sophie, cycling behind Johanna.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;小贝数了数，“有四只鹿！你可以当作是路上见到的四样东西。”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johanna counted. “There’s four of them! There you go, that’s four things for your story.”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“太好啦，”筱然感叹，“那就好写多了！”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Perfect,” Sophie exclaimed. “That’ll make it so much easier to write!”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;小鹿远远地看着两人骑车远去，继续沉浸在初日芳华的美好之中。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The little deer watched them cycle away into the distance and let itself sink back into the beauty of an awakening spring.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by dewdrop157 from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 5: Adventure Kitty</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Go outside. Put on your writer hat. Try to notice 5 things to write about! What I saw: a family having a barbecue, a butterfly pacing me on my run, a front yard full of purple hyacinths and yellow primroses, a tree hung with Easter eggs, and an adventurous cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我看到了：在烧烤的一家人，和我一起慢跑的蝴蝶，布满紫色风信子和鹅黄色樱草的前院，挂上复活节彩蛋的树 ，以及一只爱冒险的小猫咪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The breeze tickles my whiskers and I am awake. First things first, I give my body a delicious stretch. The sun warms the tips of my ears, a bumblebee buzzes through the shimmering air. Then my nose detects something wonderful. Meat on hot coals.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;微风轻挠我脸上的须，我是一只醒着的小猫。首先，我要活动下筋骨。阳光照得我耳尖暖烘烘的，一只黄蜂在晒得眩晕的空气中嗡嗡叫。我好像嗅到了什么美味，那是热碳烤肉。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The next garden is full of colour and noise. I slink around the fence, stay low to the ground. Maybe if I’m fast enough I can scavenge a scrap of meat from a plate abandoned to play. The humans and their many noises used to scare me, but I know now they mean nothing by them. They are just bad at quiet. There I spot it! Beneath the table, carelessly dropped. I pounce, bite and run, elated by my catch. I chew the juicy meat with relish.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我来到了另一户人家的花园，缤纷喧闹。我绕着栅栏不紧不慢地行走，没有一丝声响。小孩子吃烤肉吃到一半跑去玩，如果我跑得快，说不准还能捡到一块吃剩的烤肉。我平时挺怕人的，也怕他们的动静声响。不过我发现人类的声响没有特别的意思，他们只是不知道怎么安静下来。我发现了一块烤肉！就在桌底下，不小心弄掉的。我跳起来去叼肉，随即逃跑，兴奋不已。我嚼着的多汁烤肉，非常满意。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Next to me suddenly a flash of yellow. It dances up and down, back and forth. A butterfly has come to keep me company. It dashes ahead and I break into a run. Eyes fixed on the bouncing body, my feet fly over cracks in the concrete. My legs are my wings and I tango with my flighty friend.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;一抹黄影飞来我身旁，四处转动，来来回回的。原来是一只蝴蝶来陪我玩耍。我追着朝前飞舞的蝴蝶，紧盯着它摇曳的翅膀，越过了水泥地板上的缝隙。我的小猫腿如同蝴蝶的翅膀，让我随着会飞的蝴蝶朋友翩翩起舞。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Then a roar. My instincts take over and I bolt to cover. Cowered underneath a car, I turn my ears to the sound, which has morphed into a steady grumble. My heart beats wildly against my chest. I inch forwards in my hiding spot, until I can make out the garden across the street. There the butterfly still dances, now around a human pushing something in front of him. Slowly my body relaxes, and I notice a new scent. Wet grass, freshly torn from the stem. I will never get used to these howling monsters the humans keep with them, but I am glad for my fluttering friend and its serenity.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我听见一声巨响。猫咪的本能让我迅速躲到车底，抬起耳朵，注意着外界的声响，那声巨响逐渐变成平稳的嘟囔。我感受到急促的心跳。我从藏身的车底往外看，慢慢往外走，直到对面街道的花园越来越清晰。那只蝴蝶依旧起舞，只不过它现在是在一个人类跟前飞舞着。我缓缓歇息，还嗅到一种不一样的清香，是湿润小草断掉之后的味道。我一向不习惯人类这些机器的噪音，但是我为蝴蝶朋友感到高兴，因为它感觉不到这样的噪音。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I dare not move closer to the noise, so I slip into the garden behind me. Here the green grass is dotted in purple and yellow and the air is sweet. I place my paws gingerly between the dots, protecting the fragile sprouts of life around me. This is a good place to rest. Up ahead I see a tree, its twisting branches still bare, but decorated with eggs on strings in all colours of the rainbow. A fork high up in the branches is perfectly cat-shaped, I propel myself up the tree and curl up against the warm bark. As I drift off into sleep, I see a streak of yellow beside me and feel six tiny feet touch down on my nose.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;我不敢走近传来噪音的地方，我只敢悄悄走进身后的花园，翠绿的草坪上零星布满黄色紫色的小花，就连空气也是香甜的。我的爪子落在小花之间，小心护着周遭脆弱的生灵。这是休息的好地方，抬头见一树木，枝干缠绕，未见叶子，但却挂上了色彩缤纷的复活节彩蛋。树枝上还挂了一把叉子，大小恰好适宜让一只小猫躺下，我爬上树干，卷起身子，靠着暖和的树干。我快进入梦乡时，迷糊中看到一抹黄颜色，只觉有六只小小的脚丫落在我的鼻子上。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Kessa from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>第四天：她的秘密</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a secret you or a character have been keeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;丽塔是一个普通的高中生，平时就忙着读书考试，偶尔写写日记，最期待的就是周末和放假。她有一个小秘密，自13岁生日以后，她能够在睡梦中穿越回古代。两年的时光旅行者睡梦生涯让丽塔很有动力去查阅史料，了解不同的风俗和学习新的语言。她也不知道梦究竟会把她带到何处，好在时光穿梭梦像电视连续剧，一个故事完结才进入下一个故事。目前为止，她已经到过平安时代的日本和盛唐时期的中国。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rita was an ordinary high school student, usually busy with studying and exams. She kept a diary and she loved weekends and school breaks above anything else. But she had a secret. When she was 13, she started travelling back in time in her dreams. Two years of dream time-travelling had spurred her on to dig out historical sources, discover past customs and learn new languages. Although she could never be sure where her dreams would take her, they helpfully played out like episodes of a TV series. She only moved on somewhere new after she had completed a story arc. In her dreams she had already visited Heian period Japan and China in its Golden Age, the Tang dynasty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;昨晚梦里丽塔又开始了一段全新的冒险，她在迷糊的睡梦中到达了静寂的小山村附近，抬眼望去，除了碧蓝的天空外，还可见到高耸入云的雪山。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Last night, Rita’s dreams took her on a new adventure. Emerging from indistinct blurs, she found herself outside a quiet village surrounded by mountains. Looking up she saw the blue sky stretching over her head, and below it cloudy peaks capped in white.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;睡醒的丽塔来到书桌旁，翻开日记本，记录起梦中的见闻：&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As soon as she woke up, Rita opened her diary at her desk and wrote down what she had seen:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;梦里到了不知在哪儿的小山村，附近有漂亮的雪山，天气很好，日照时间很长，应该是在高纬度地区吧。周围村民讲什么我都听不懂，他们都是白人，穿着当地的传统服饰，见到我都很惊讶，盯着我看，弄到我都不好意思了，还好他们没把我抓起来拷问。他们也许从来没有见过长相异域的东方人吧。村里有一座教堂，有圆圆的拱顶，应该是东正教堂吧。那我猜测，梦里的地方应该是在东欧吧。后来，有一个金发碧眼的可爱女孩子来和我搭讪，她和我年龄相仿。我听不懂她说什么，但是凭借肢体语言和各种比划，我们好像可以交流一下，她的名字听起来是Elena… …或许我今天放学之后需要上网搜索一下有关东欧的资料吧，至少查一下有什么文化禁忌，不要冒犯到当地人。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Last night, I went to a village in the mountains, I don’t know where. The peaks were snowy. The weather was good and the sun stayed up for a long time. A high latitude probably. I couldn’t understand a word the locals were saying. They were all white and seemed to be wearing traditional clothes. They were are all shocked to see me and kept throwing glances at me. It was lucky I made it out without them forcing me into a cross-examination. They’ve probably never seen an Asian like me. At some point, a little girl with blonde hair and green eyes came up to talk to me, she seemed to be my age. Even though I didn’t know what she was saying, we could communicate a little bit with our hands and feet. Her name sounds like Elena. Maybe after school today I’ll do some research on Eastern Europe, at least I should know what the taboos are, don’t want to get on the locals’ bad side.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;丽塔记录完梦里的内容便合上日记本，换好校服，洗漱干净，背上书包，出门上学。虽然她有不为人知的冒险旅途，但至少表面上看，她还是一个普通得不能在普通的高中生了，还是要好好读书，参加高考的普通15岁女生。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After finishing her entry, Rita shut her diary, put on her school uniform, had a wash, picked up her backpack and left for school. And even if she had just been on an extraordinary adventure, from the outside she still looked like an ordinary 15-year-old high school student studying hard for her exams.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by simplyelke from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Day 4: Charlie&#39;s Secret</title>
        <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/</guid>
        <description>Quarantine Chronicles /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/ -&lt;p&gt;Write about a secret you or a character have been keeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;中文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charlie was still giggling when she unlocked the front door. Jess had been so funny, imitating Mr Hobbs, their maths teacher. “How many times do I have to tell you, right angles are per-pen-dicular!” She had a way of getting it just right, the way he spat out his p’s, like he wanted to slingshot them straight into your brain. “Repeat after me Charlie, pa-per, pers-piration, per-plexed, pep-per…”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;夏丽回家开门时，依旧笑容满面。杰西模仿数学老师霍博思先生的样子实在是太搞笑了。“要和你们讲多少次，直角可是吃-维-垂直的！”她学得有模有样，学着他说话的样子，仿佛想把知识活生生地塞进他们脑子里。“跟着我念，吃-污-出汗，困惑，科-问-困……”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pur-ple pa-prika Charlie thought as she walked down the corridor, that’s a good one. Pep-peroni pizza. “How was your day honey?”, her mother shouted from the kitchen, “still hungry?” “I ate at Jess’,” Charlie replied, already halfway up the stairs. Going into the kitchen at this hour was dangerous. She loved her parents in the morning, she really did. But in the evening, they were a complete disaster. All they wanted to do was talk. It would start with “anything interesting happen at school today?” and wouldn’t end before they hadn’t extracted from her every minute detail of her day. She supposed old people needed the entertainment. Her parents both worked at the city library. They woke up together, had breakfast (her father made the tea, her mother the porridge), went to work together and walked home together. Sometimes it seemed to her like over all their years together, always together, they had forgotten how to talk to each other.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;夏丽到了长廊仍在回忆杰西洗脑般的模仿，学的太像了。“宝贝，今天过得怎么样？”妈妈在厨房里大声喊道，“饿了吗？”“我在杰西家吃了点东西，”夏丽回答，她快走到楼上了。这可不是去厨房的时间。夏丽喜欢父母白天的样子，真的。但晚上还是算了，晚上见到爸妈可怕极了，他们只想一直打听她的事情，往往都是从一个问题开始：“今天在学校有没有什么好玩的事啊？”更可怕的是，她不详细说清楚当天发生的事情，父母都不会罢休。夏丽觉得上了年纪的人是需要点茶余饭后的消遣。夏丽的父母都在市图书馆工作，同时起床，爸爸泡茶，妈妈煮粥，一同用早餐，一起上下班。夏丽偶尔觉得父母一年四季都在一起，总是粘在一起，以至于他们都不记得如何跟对方沟通了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tonight, Charlie didn’t feel like stepping in for their entertainment. She didn’t want her day dissected until it didn’t feel whole anymore. It had been too precious. And she was worried. Worried that her parents would notice something in the way she spoke about Jess. Worried that they could see the butterflies tickling her insides whenever she thought about her. She so desperately wanted to keep them secret, keep them safe. In Biology they had learned that butterfly wings were so fragile that one touch, one raindrop might be enough to break them. So she knew she couldn’t let them out, couldn’t let her parents see.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;今晚，夏丽不想被父母消遣，不想和他们汇报所有的细节。今天实在是太难得了，所以夏丽有些担心，害怕父母会注意到她谈到杰西时会整个人都不一样，会发现她变得无比开心。夏丽只想守护好自己的秘密，确保自己的秘密是安全的。生物课上说蝴蝶翅膀极为脆弱，经不起轻轻碰触或是一颗雨滴的重量。所以，夏丽深知要守护好如同蝴蝶翅膀一般的秘密，绝对不能让父母听到一丝风声。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;She closed her door tightly behind her. On her desk sat a plate of cookies, steaming still from the oven. Sometimes her parents weren’t too bad she supposed. Her pocket pinged.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;她关紧房门。书桌上摆放着一盘饼干，新鲜出炉，仍冒着蒸汽。夏丽想，父母也没那么烦吧。她的口袋里传来一丝声响，是杰西发的信息。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jess: What are you up to?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;杰西：你在干嘛？&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charlie: Just thinking about butterflies. You?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;夏丽：在想蝴蝶呢。你呢？&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jess: Haha really? You know I used to collect butterflies, seems sadistic in hindsight though.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;杰西：哈哈真的假的？我以前收集过蝴蝶，后来发现有点残忍。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charlie: You preposterous person…Mr Hobbs is disappointed in you.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;夏丽：你这大傻瓜… 霍博思先生对你可失望了。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jess: I know, I’ll personally apologise to him tomorrow.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;杰西：我知道，我明天会和他道歉的。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charlie took a bite of her cookie and felt a warmth spreading throughout her. It really was sadistic she thought to herself, keeping butterflies locked up. One day she would let them out.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;夏丽吃了一口仍然温暖的饼干，那股暖意传遍全身。真的很残忍啊，她思索着，把蝴蝶锁起来真的很残忍。或许某天，她能够把心中的蝴蝶释放出来。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Schwoaze from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
- /johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/ - Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 