<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>translated by Sophie on Quarantine Chronicles</title>
    <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/tags/translated-by-sophie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in translated by Sophie on Quarantine Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:00:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/johannabernatzky.github.io/tags/translated-by-sophie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9: Full Moon at Orchard House</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/1-april/</guid>
      <description>Write about a celebration.
   English 中文     Leon lived on the tenth floor of Orchard House. Whoever had chosen this name must have possessed an obscene dose of optimism, Orchard House was about as far from green as you could get. Layers of concrete squashed over each other, the building imposed its presence on the neighbourhood like a prison guard. Try as you might, wherever you went one of its windows was watching you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8: Alone at Lidl</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/31-march/</guid>
      <description>Write a poem full of social distance.
   English 中文     I wonder why 我想知道   We don’t look at each other anymore 大家为何不再看彼此一眼       Pushing our shopping carts 推挤着购物车   past each other 经 过 彼此       We stare resolutely ahead 我们盯着远处   Or find a particularly eye-catching 或是发现了特别抢眼的       bunch 一   of 束   bananas to investigate 香蕉用来观察       Maybe we are scared 也许我们都害怕   That this small human interaction might be enough 人与人之间小小的互动就足以   To contaminate uswithcloseness 让对方染病   Twometresdisappearoverthemeetingofeyes 一旦对视两米的社交距离就会凭空消失       Or maybe we cannot bear it 或许我们无法忍受   It hurts too much to see and not touch, not hug, not hold 见到彼此，却无法碰触，拥抱，握手       Today I am resolved to look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7: Lady of the Castle</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/30-march/</guid>
      <description>Write a story about a ghost.
   English 中文     I was born during a dreadful winter storm in the servants’ quarters at a great castle. I never met the lords and ladies who belonged upstairs in the satin-stuffed rooms. My mother deemed me too young, too loud, too filthy and so the kitchen was where I spent most of my time. One of the stern-faced men whose portraits now stared us down from in between marble columns had cherished solitude and quiet so much that he had banished the busy kitchen from the castle keep entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6: Nu Dans un Intérieur</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/</guid>
      <description>Write about a painting you find online or on your walls.
   English 中文     This morning I woke up feeling fluffy inside and out. The soft pillow against my cheek, the aftereffects of a generous helping of vino. My nose was the first thing to spring into action. The faint smell of coffee drifting in from somewhere carried promise. I sat up in bed, slowly to not upset the cotton filling my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5: Adventure Kitty</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/</guid>
      <description>Go outside. Put on your writer hat. Try to notice 5 things to write about! What I saw: a family having a barbecue, a butterfly pacing me on my run, a front yard full of purple hyacinths and yellow primroses, a tree hung with Easter eggs, and an adventurous cat.
我看到了：在烧烤的一家人，和我一起慢跑的蝴蝶，布满紫色风信子和鹅黄色樱草的前院，挂上复活节彩蛋的树 ，以及一只爱冒险的小猫咪。
   English 中文     The breeze tickles my whiskers and I am awake. First things first, I give my body a delicious stretch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4: Charlie&#39;s Secret</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/</guid>
      <description>Write about a secret you or a character have been keeping.
   English 中文     Charlie was still giggling when she unlocked the front door. Jess had been so funny, imitating Mr Hobbs, their maths teacher. “How many times do I have to tell you, right angles are per-pen-dicular!” She had a way of getting it just right, the way he spat out his p’s, like he wanted to slingshot them straight into your brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: The Cursor&#39;s Lament</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/26-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/26-march/</guid>
      <description>Set your text to white and try freewriting in invisible mode.
   English 中文     Where am I? Everything is bright, I have forgotten my past, I don’t know my future. All I have is now, an existence barely there. I am flickering in and out of consciousness. I feel something. A rhythm is driving me forwards. In and out and in and out. What am I running towards?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Behind the Waterfall</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/25-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/25-march/</guid>
      <description>Pick 5 words at random from different blog posts, tweets, or articles and use them all in a scene. Social distance, tourist attraction, currywurst, cherry blossoms, virtual kiss. 个人空间、景点、咖喱香肠、樱花、隔空亲吻.
   English 中文     Deep in the mountains, hidden behind a gurgling waterfall, lies a secret land. Only the rarest souls find its entrance. Hikers marvel at the refreshing mist, check a tourist attraction off their list, send their loved ones photographic evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: But Why Can&#39;t I Go Out?</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/24-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/24-march/</guid>
      <description>Write about a character who&amp;rsquo;s stuck inside. How do they feel about it? Why are they there?
   English 中文     “But why can’t I go out mum?” asked the little meerkat. It was barely a few weeks old, silver fluff still covered its fur like cobwebs. A meerkat’s favourite place to be is in the scorching sun. Coming out from the dark tunnels with their twists and turns, the eyes take a while to adjust.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>