<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Story on Quarantine Chronicles</title>
    <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/categories/story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Story on Quarantine Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Johanna 小贝 and Sophie 筱然 2020.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/johannabernatzky.github.io/categories/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>第六天：一幅画，两棵树</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-29/</guid>
      <description>Write about a painting you find online or on your walls.
   中文 English     床头的画中有两颗生长在一起的大树，颜色一深一浅，枝干不多，绿意盎然。 In the painting at the foot of bed there are two trees twisted into each other. One is light, one is dark. Their branches are few in number but rich in green.   看见树，想到尼采的《查拉图斯特拉如是说》，他写道：“其实人跟树是一样的，越是向往高处的阳光，它的根就越要伸向黑暗的地底”。随着年龄的增长，愈发觉得人总要直视自己的黑暗面，才能让光明的那面更好地生长，也明白单纯不和善良挂钩，人可以有过痛苦的经历，见过世间的残酷，依旧保有纯粹美好的一面，做出充满善意的选择。 The trees remind me of this quote from Nietzsche’s “Thus Spoke Zarathustra”: “But it is the same with man as with the tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6: Nu Dans un Intérieur</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/29-march/</guid>
      <description>Write about a painting you find online or on your walls.
   English 中文     This morning I woke up feeling fluffy inside and out. The soft pillow against my cheek, the aftereffects of a generous helping of vino. My nose was the first thing to spring into action. The faint smell of coffee drifting in from somewhere carried promise. I sat up in bed, slowly to not upset the cotton filling my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第五天：小鹿的樱花梦</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-28/</guid>
      <description>Go outside. Put on your writer hat. Try to notice 5 things to write about!
   中文 English     小鹿和家人在田野里悠转，享受温暖和煦的阳光，吃着田间植被与落叶。明天要转夏令时了，小鹿兴奋地期待着，春天来了，天气应该会更舒服吧。 The little deer treaded lightly on the field, basking in the warm sunlight, grazing on plants and fallen leaves. It was the day before summer time and the little deer was excited. Spring was coming and with it the warmer temperatures it liked.   最近的气温足够暖和，迎来了初春的花期，花树开始初吐芬芳，其中包括小鹿最喜欢的樱花树了。田野附近的樱花树已是娇艳盛开，每一朵小巧的樱花都微不足道，但仔细观看，层层重瓣繁复华丽。满树樱花蔚为观止，小鹿忍不住想象再过些时日，如若起风，樱花随风飘舞，如同落雪的美丽。啊，到时它可以在堆在地上的柔软落花里打滚，沾染樱花浅淡的馨香，亦或是把自己埋在花堆里，把陨落质柔的花瓣当作棉被，抵挡初春的清寒，它还可以尝尝樱花滋味，毕竟平时吃的都是绿色植被，难得有粉色的食材可用…… The mild air had already blown in the first flowers of early spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5: Adventure Kitty</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/28-march/</guid>
      <description>Go outside. Put on your writer hat. Try to notice 5 things to write about! What I saw: a family having a barbecue, a butterfly pacing me on my run, a front yard full of purple hyacinths and yellow primroses, a tree hung with Easter eggs, and an adventurous cat.
我看到了：在烧烤的一家人，和我一起慢跑的蝴蝶，布满紫色风信子和鹅黄色樱草的前院，挂上复活节彩蛋的树 ，以及一只爱冒险的小猫咪。
   English 中文     The breeze tickles my whiskers and I am awake. First things first, I give my body a delicious stretch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第四天：她的秘密</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-27/</guid>
      <description>Write about a secret you or a character have been keeping.
   中文 English     丽塔是一个普通的高中生，平时就忙着读书考试，偶尔写写日记，最期待的就是周末和放假。她有一个小秘密，自13岁生日以后，她能够在睡梦中穿越回古代。两年的时光旅行者睡梦生涯让丽塔很有动力去查阅史料，了解不同的风俗和学习新的语言。她也不知道梦究竟会把她带到何处，好在时光穿梭梦像电视连续剧，一个故事完结才进入下一个故事。目前为止，她已经到过平安时代的日本和盛唐时期的中国。 Rita was an ordinary high school student, usually busy with studying and exams. She kept a diary and she loved weekends and school breaks above anything else. But she had a secret. When she was 13, she started travelling back in time in her dreams. Two years of dream time-travelling had spurred her on to dig out historical sources, discover past customs and learn new languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4: Charlie&#39;s Secret</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/27-march/</guid>
      <description>Write about a secret you or a character have been keeping.
   English 中文     Charlie was still giggling when she unlocked the front door. Jess had been so funny, imitating Mr Hobbs, their maths teacher. “How many times do I have to tell you, right angles are per-pen-dicular!” She had a way of getting it just right, the way he spat out his p’s, like he wanted to slingshot them straight into your brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第三天：今天的挑战</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:45:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-26/</guid>
      <description>Set your text to white and try freewriting in invisible mode.
   中文 English     今天的新挑战，把字体颜色调成白色进行记录，无法看到自己打的是什么字，总之就这样一直码字码下去，但是偶尔出现的蓝色红色波浪线像是举着牌子表示这里有点可疑！ Today’s challenge is to set your font to white and type. This way you can’t see what you’re typing, letter after letter you put in, only the odd blue and red line pops up like a warning sign, you’ve typed something suspicious here!   有一部日本动画《工作细胞》讲述了人类身体里面运作的各类细胞，这部动画以一种很可爱的方式给我们科普。里面的细胞形象都非常可爱。原来人体里面有那么多的细胞在努力工作，我们的身体才能够好好的运作。 “Cells at Work” is an anime series about the work all the little cells in our bodies do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: The Cursor&#39;s Lament</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/26-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/26-march/</guid>
      <description>Set your text to white and try freewriting in invisible mode.
   English 中文     Where am I? Everything is bright, I have forgotten my past, I don’t know my future. All I have is now, an existence barely there. I am flickering in and out of consciousness. I feel something. A rhythm is driving me forwards. In and out and in and out. What am I running towards?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第二天：网红熊猫的诞生</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 18:01:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-25/</guid>
      <description>Pick 5 words at random from different blog posts, tweets, or articles and use them all in a scene. 熊猫、烦躁、郁金香、早饭、月球. Panda, annoyed, tulip, breakfast, moon.
   中文 English     胖达是一只毛茸茸的熊猫，她生活在文化多元的伦敦。胖达偶尔不是那么有耐心，一旦要排队挤地铁，她就会有点烦躁。 In the cultured city of London lives a cuddly panda. She goes by Panda. A bit impatient, queuing for the tube often annoys her.   胖达在伦敦最大的动物园工作，一到动物园她就会和其他员工一样打卡签到。与其他工作人员不同的是，签到之后，胖达就会进入到熊猫馆，在那里待上大半天。她的工作就是向人们展示普通熊猫的生活，在熊猫馆里面和其他熊猫朋友嬉戏打闹，啃啃竹子，吃吃水果，玩累了就睡个觉，到了下班时间就离馆回家。然而，胖达偶尔有些小郁闷，担心在动物园里向人类展示的熊猫生活会加深人们对熊猫的刻板印象，因为在现代社会里，熊猫除了吃喝玩乐，享受生活之外，还是有很多追求的，而胖达无法在动物园里展示熊猫生活的另一面。 Panda works in the biggest zoo in London. When she arrives for work, she swipes in just like her co-workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Behind the Waterfall</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/25-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 18:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/25-march/</guid>
      <description>Pick 5 words at random from different blog posts, tweets, or articles and use them all in a scene. Social distance, tourist attraction, currywurst, cherry blossoms, virtual kiss. 个人空间、景点、咖喱香肠、樱花、隔空亲吻.
   English 中文     Deep in the mountains, hidden behind a gurgling waterfall, lies a secret land. Only the rarest souls find its entrance. Hikers marvel at the refreshing mist, check a tourist attraction off their list, send their loved ones photographic evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第一天：闭门保命的日子</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:30:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/3-yue-24/</guid>
      <description>Write about a character who&amp;rsquo;s stuck inside. How do they feel about it? Why are they there?
   中文 English     近日，一种丧尸病毒席卷欧洲，活人若是遭到丧尸啃咬，轻则收点皮肉伤，加以治疗，仍能恢复过上正常生活，重则失去自由意志，成为胡乱咬人丧尸部队一员。为了群众避免无辜受伤，各国政府进入紧急状态，宣布宵禁措施，限制公民活动。 A zombie virus is spreading around Europe. A bite that only barely breaks the skin can be treated and the victims continue their lives as before, the severe bites however bleed out a person’s free will and force them into the ranks of ravaging zombies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: But Why Can&#39;t I Go Out?</title>
      <link>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/24-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/johannabernatzky.github.io/posts/24-march/</guid>
      <description>Write about a character who&amp;rsquo;s stuck inside. How do they feel about it? Why are they there?
   English 中文     “But why can’t I go out mum?” asked the little meerkat. It was barely a few weeks old, silver fluff still covered its fur like cobwebs. A meerkat’s favourite place to be is in the scorching sun. Coming out from the dark tunnels with their twists and turns, the eyes take a while to adjust.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>